<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Podcast on I learnt ...</title>
    <link>https://ilearnt.com/categories/podcast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Podcast on I learnt ...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 08:10:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ilearnt.com/categories/podcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Technology Less Manipulative</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/technologymanipulative/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 08:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/technologymanipulative/</guid>
      <description>This was an excellent podcast on the ethics behind some of the decisions being made about technology today. The whole talk is excellent and thought provoking however for me one part (about 27 minutes in) stood out:
&amp;ldquo;When we think about AI we have to remember you know when you point the AI system at chess, right, first it kind of wiggles around and it makes some kind of funny looking moves and then it starts making some smart moves as it gets better and then it makes some surprisingly smart moves and then it beats Garry Kasparov.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphic Design for Films</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/filmgraphicdesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 08:43:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/filmgraphicdesign/</guid>
      <description>I listen to a lot of podcasts (probably 500+ a year) and one I make an extra effort to listen to every episode is 99% Invisible. It is &amp;ldquo;about all the thought that goes into the things we don’t think about — the unnoticed architecture and design that shape our world.&amp;rdquo;
I was catching up on past episodes and came across one that made me think about a whole area that I had never considered but in hindsight seems obvious that someone needs to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>