<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technology on I learnt about ...</title>
    <link>https://ilearnt.com/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technology on I learnt about ...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 20:50:08 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ilearnt.com/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>When your WPF menu alignment is wrong</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/menualignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 20:50:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/menualignment/</guid>
      <description>I had a very weird problem where my menus on a WPF application were dropping down to the left instead of the normal to the right.
 Incorrect menu alignment   It turns out it is due to having a tablet setting set to right handed &amp;hellip; even though I don&amp;rsquo;t have a tablet. The answer was found on the link at the bottom of this post.
To fix it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A quick fix for missing Gmail notifications on Android phones</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/gmailsyncissueonandroid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 17:39:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/gmailsyncissueonandroid/</guid>
      <description>I occasionally stop getting Gmail notifications on my Google Pixel 2XL android phone. I later find that I have a whole bunch of emails that I had missed. I am not sure what causes it however I have found a way to make it work again.
Under Settings, select Accounts and then your Google account. Once opened click on Account sync. You will be able to see when it was last synced and you will probably find that it failed a while ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fastest way to switch Gmail accounts on Android phones</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/cyclethroughgmailaccountsonandroid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 21:36:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/cyclethroughgmailaccountsonandroid/</guid>
      <description>Using Gmail on Android it is possible to support multiple email accounts. The normal way you can change which account you are looking at is by pressing on the account picture in the top right hand corner and then selecting the user.
However I found a potentially quicker approach completely by accident. If you press on the picture as before then drag down you can cycle through the email accounts one by one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally a to-do app I use ... Microsoft To Do</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/microsofttodo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 14:28:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/microsofttodo/</guid>
      <description>I have tried numerous to-do applications in the past; from the very simplest to the all-singing, all-dancing applications and they have never stuck. I used them for a week or so and realised a month later that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t used them for a while.
The Microsoft To Do application seems to have hit a sweet spot for me. I have found myself using it regularly to track both my home and my work tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goggles give back sight</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/gogglesgivebacksight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 07:33:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/gogglesgivebacksight/</guid>
      <description>This short clip is pretty remarkable. A young woman lost most of her sight due to a brain tumour. All she has left is a small blurry circle in her right eye. With the use of some AR goggles and some very clever tech she was able to read for the first time in years - very moving.
Links
Goggles &amp;lsquo;give back&amp;rsquo; sight to Maisy so she can read again</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazy programmers can be the most productive</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/lazyprogrammers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 08:07:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/lazyprogrammers/</guid>
      <description>There is often a work culture that you should be busy all the time - if you are a programmer you should always be typing and producing code. Programming is a mental process and so requires thinking. Sometimes a little thought upfront saves a lot of pain and work down the line.
The article below has a potentially controversial headline but sums this up really well. Being perceived as lazy as a programmer can actually be a good thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical debt is like Tetris</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/technicaldebttetris/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 07:05:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/technicaldebttetris/</guid>
      <description>This article uses a really neat analogy with Tetris for illustrating the impact of technical debt. Leaving gaps is akin to leaving technical debt in the code base and makes subsequent changes more difficult or slower to ship.
 A buried gap in Tetris represents technical debt.
 It also points out the fact that it is called debt and so has to be paid off at some point.
 Paying down technical debt keeps you competitive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The value of throwing code away</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/throwawaycode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 08:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/throwawaycode/</guid>
      <description>We had a discussion at work about &amp;ldquo;throw away&amp;rdquo; code. One of our developers was very against developing any code that would be thrown away afterwards. He referred to this as a waste. In my view sometimes the biggest gain can be in developing code that is meant to be thrown away. It can be used to try things and, more importantly, learn things that can shape the code that is kept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating 3D animations from a 2D photo</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/3dfrom2d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 10:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/3dfrom2d/</guid>
      <description>This is a pretty amazing demonstration of animating an aspect of a 2d photo. This even includes pulling out bodies and animating them moving away from their original scene.
If we can simulate video in this way then can we ever still believe video as proof of what has happened?
Links
Photo Wake-Up: 3D Character Animation from a Single Photo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Mirror - technology ethics and can it be used for wrong?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/blackmirrortesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 08:15:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/blackmirrortesting/</guid>
      <description>Nearly every technology that has been developed has been used for both good and bad. Developments that look like they could have a massive impact on civilization have usually also spun off a side effect that has a detrimental effect. This could be the latest technologies such as genetic engineering and artificial intelligence or older technologies such as the automobile.
This article discusses using an exercise during the development of the technology to identify these wrong uses and how/if they can be alleviated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Github SSH</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/githubssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 14:00:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/githubssh/</guid>
      <description>Just a reminder of the starting point for setting up SSH with Github so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to keep looking for it each time.
Links
Connecting to GitHub with SSH</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git - what to do when it goes wrong</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/flightrulesforgit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 16:45:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/flightrulesforgit/</guid>
      <description>This has a great summary of what to do when things go wrong when using Git. Added here so I know where to look in moments of panic.
Links
Flight Rules for Git</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The secret history of Ctrl&#43;Alt&#43;Del</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/altcontroldelete/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 17:04:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/altcontroldelete/</guid>
      <description>The background to why the famous &amp;ldquo;three finger salute&amp;rdquo; was chosen to be so difficult to do.
Links
The secret history of Ctrl+Alt+Del</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scala &#43; Sbt &#43; Docker quickly</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/scaladocker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 07:42:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/scaladocker/</guid>
      <description>I am currently starting to learn Scala (to add to a myriad of other languages I have programmed in over my career). We are also in the process of &amp;ldquo;dockerizing&amp;rdquo; our application. So I wanted to try for myself getting a simple Scala application running in Docker.
This page has a very simple guide to getting a &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; application up and running.
Links
Getting Started With Docker, Scala &amp;amp; Sbt</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abandoning the baggage of Agile</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/developersshouldabandonagile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 06:46:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/developersshouldabandonagile/</guid>
      <description>I have worked with various flavours of &amp;ldquo;Agile&amp;rdquo; over numerous years. These have ranged from the very formal where everything is done by the book to more ad-hoc versions where different parts are cherry picked or in most cases done because people think they should be done.
What is clear is that &amp;ldquo;Agile&amp;rdquo; has become more about the processes than about the results and the actual aims of the original manifesto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The legacy vulnerability of the Internet</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/networkdevelopments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 06:51:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/networkdevelopments/</guid>
      <description>This article documents developments over the last ten years at all layers of the network stack. It also highlights how vulnerable the current Internet is.
Links
Another ten years later</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In a distributed system ... there is no now</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/thereisnonow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 07:41:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/thereisnonow/</guid>
      <description>This paper is a discussion around the issues faced by distributed systems when dealing with time, ordering and failures. This is particularly relevant with the work I am doing at the moment designing a very large distributed system that will need to scale massively.
It is remarkably readable and illustrates key issues and limitations in the field. It has already got me researching other areas mentioned in the paper.
Links</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Hitchhiker’s Guide to Consensus Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/consensusalgorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 07:18:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/consensusalgorithms/</guid>
      <description>This is a summary of a number of consensus algorithms currently being used in the Blockchain space. The most common at the moment is Proof of Work however this is slowly being replaced by other approaches that are more performant and don&amp;rsquo;t use all the Earth&amp;rsquo;s energy.
Links
A Hitchhiker’s Guide to Consensus Algorithms</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REST API Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/restapiguidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 08:15:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/restapiguidelines/</guid>
      <description>This is here for future reference - a very good set of guidelines for REST APIs.
Links
Zalando RESTful API and Event Scheme Guidelines</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The accelerated pace of image processing developments</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/imageprocessingdevelopments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 07:19:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/imageprocessingdevelopments/</guid>
      <description>There are some amazing things happening with image processing at the moment. I remember my graphics class at university 25 years ago and the primitive, by comparison to now, image processing algorithms we had to code. Oh how things have moved on.
The first link below is some incredible work to make very low light images intelligible. The example results are quite incredible - making a viewable image out of an image that looks completely dark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making the explanation of distributed systems fun</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/explainingdistributedsystems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 08:45:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/explainingdistributedsystems/</guid>
      <description>I love the way this article explains some of the key issues with designing distributed systems and how to solve them. It uses the illustration of a theme park and the rides - very clever and a fun read, which is unusual for a distributed systems article!
Links
Maximizing fun (and profit) in your distributed systems</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A MacBook touchscreen for only $1</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/macbooktouchscreen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 08:09:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/macbooktouchscreen/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t own, and have no intention of owning, a MacBook as I own a touchscreen Windows laptop however this approach to make it support touch is genius. They use a mirror at the top of the screen and some image processing to work out where the finger is. They can determine if the finger is actually touching the screen by whether it is touching its reflection - very clever lateral thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is &#39;just&#39; ...</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/just/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 21:00:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/just/</guid>
      <description>It is very easy to make assumptions about a subject you know well and others may not. You will have knowledge you have learnt over time that you perceive is so simple or obvious that others should just know it - forgetting that once you too had to learn it. This article sums it up really well with the word &amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;just&amp;rdquo;.
Links
Just</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The term &#39;Blockchain&#39; is meaningless</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/blockchainmeaningless/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 08:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/blockchainmeaningless/</guid>
      <description>There seems to be no single clean definition of what &amp;ldquo;Blockchain&amp;rdquo; actually means. There are a lot of woolly statements, several of which are clearly either wrong or too narrowly focused. This article goes into some of the different definitions and why they are wrong and then the implications of this from a business but also a legal perspective.
I personally think the definition by Mike Gault, CEO of Guardtime, is the closest:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using AI to find code problems</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/aicodeassistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 14:55:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/aicodeassistant/</guid>
      <description>Ubissoft have introduced a tool that &amp;ldquo;uses AI&amp;rdquo; to identify potential coding issues when the developer commits code. They claim it can detect a significant number of errors and even suggest solutions in some cases. There will always be some errors that it will not be able to identify, for example where the implementation doesn&amp;rsquo;t match the requirements, however this approach could have a significant impact on the amount of time spent debugging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the team size to deliver</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/reducingteamsize/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 18:15:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/reducingteamsize/</guid>
      <description>A project was struggling to deliver in time and the project manager resolved it by reducing the team size where the typical approach is to increase the team size. This decision was based on the overhead of communication and Brooks Law.
Links
Applying Brooks Law</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer platforms must listen to developers in order to grow</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/developerplatforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 21:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/developerplatforms/</guid>
      <description>This is an excellent study on why developers are so important to a platform. At the moment we are developing a platform and we have been trying to get this message across to the business side of the company. This article backs up what we have been saying.
 &amp;ldquo;This means that platform makers must listen and learn how developers want their platforms marketed to them and must work to help developers find interesting ways to solve tough problems using their platforms, he added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do crypto-currencies work?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/howdocryptocurrencieswork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 07:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/howdocryptocurrencieswork/</guid>
      <description>A very simple introduction to how Bitcoin works &amp;hellip; using a stuffed penguin!
Links
Bitcoin explained: How do crypto-currencies work?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making technology less manipulative</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/technologymanipulative/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 08:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/technologymanipulative/</guid>
      <description>This was an excellent podcast on the ethics behind some of the decisions being made about technology today. The whole talk is excellent and thought provoking however for me one part (about 27 minutes in) stood out:
 &amp;ldquo;When we think about AI we have to remember you know when you point the AI system at chess, right, first it kind of wiggles around and it makes some kind of funny looking moves and then it starts making some smart moves as it gets better and then it makes some surprisingly smart moves and then it beats Garry Kasparov.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart glasses you might actually wear</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/intelvaunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 21:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/intelvaunt/</guid>
      <description>Intel have just announced a new set of smart glasses that don&amp;rsquo;t look stupid. Admittedly the functionality is a lot more limited that other offerings however these look a lot more normal than them. It provides very limited functionality to display a small red image in the lower part of the wearers vision. Cleverly it also disappears when the user is not looking down.
They have some grand plans for it but I do question whether the limited display provides enough functionality to get users to use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending a wifi network with a TP-Link RE650</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/re650/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 21:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/re650/</guid>
      <description>I had a very unusual setup for the network for my office. The office is situated a floor above and at the opposite end of the house to where the main router is located. A fully wired connection is not an option at the moment due to concrete floors and limited access to roof voids.
Previously this meant using a wireless extender into the room above the router and then using HomePlugs to connect to the office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professionals do everything necessary - not just the fun bits</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/professional/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 15:46:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/professional/</guid>
      <description>This article defines the difference between a professional developer and an amateur as:
A professional always does everything necessary to complete a job. An amateur sometimes chooses only the fun parts.
It goes on further to say that the amateur only codes what they have been told; the professional bring &amp;ldquo;their full brain, experience and creativity&amp;rdquo;. To be professional is to go the extra mile, think about the work and deliver something that delivers what is needed (which is not necessarily what has been defined).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain - what impact will it have?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/35blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 20:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/35blockchain/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of stories around how Blockchain could revolutionize every industry. This is a nice summary of some of the companies that are trying to make this happen and the way they are trying to make an impact.
Links
Real World Examples</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology - Am I past it?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/pastit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 16:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/pastit/</guid>
      <description>This is an interesting post from Rob Conery, someone I&amp;rsquo;ve followed for quite some time, and his observations as he gets older about how he wonders if he is past keeping up with new technology.
I regularly get challenged with new roles and new technologies and often question myself but experience counts for a lot and life would be boring without challenges :)
Links
Modern Dev Team</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with the Hugo static site generator</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 16:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/hugo/</guid>
      <description>This blog is being powered by a static content generator called Hugo and hosted on GitHub Pages. Getting Hugo up and running was relatively easy. Download the relevant version and installation was just copying it to a folder.
Once installed, create a new site:
​	hugo new site mySite
In the site folder edit the config.toml file to change the baseUrl, the language and the title.
Use git to clone a theme from the available themes to a folder under the themes folder in your site.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>