<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ILearnt</title>
    <link>https://ilearnt.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ILearnt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 07:46:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ilearnt.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ma’agalim - Jane Bordeaux</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/maagalim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 07:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/maagalim/</guid>
      <description>This is a beautiful music video. Watch it all the way through and carefully watch what happens to some of the characters.
Links
Ma’agalim - Jane Bordeaux</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professionals v Amateurs</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/professional/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 15:46:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/professional/</guid>
      <description>This article defines the difference between a professional developer and an amateur as:
A professional always does everything necessary to complete a job. An amateur sometimes chooses only the fun parts.
It goes on further to say that the amateur only codes what they have been told; the professional bring &amp;ldquo;their full brain, experience and creativity&amp;rdquo;. To be professional is to go the extra mile, think about the work and deliver something that delivers what is needed (which is not necessarily what has been defined).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kubernetes Book by Nigel Poulton</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/thekubernetesbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 07:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/thekubernetesbook/</guid>
      <description>At the moment I am having to get up to speed on a bunch of technologies relating to &amp;ldquo;DevOps&amp;rdquo;. This includes Kubernetes. I borrowed this book from a colleague and read it over the course of two days commuting. It provides a very good high level overview of all the main concepts of the platform.
As an introduction, which is exactly what I needed, it was perfectly pitched however if I was going to have to get my hands dirty with using the platform in anger then there are probably better options out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When The Game Was Ours by Jackie MacMullan, Larry Bird, and Magic Johnson</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/whenthegamewasours/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 07:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/whenthegamewasours/</guid>
      <description>On 12th June 1984 I was on a family holiday in the US. We had spent three weeks travelling around Florida and then up the east coast to finally end up in Boston. During the day we had a guided tour of the city and we were told that it was game seven of the NBA finals that night between the Boston Celtics and the Los Angeles Lakers.
I was only thirteen but, possibly as it was the last night of the holiday, managed to persuade my parents that I could stay up and watch the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crazy Socks</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/crazysocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 13:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/crazysocks/</guid>
      <description>This is a great article about a small business that is growing rapidly and run with a smile on their faces. John and his dad started a business to sell crazy, fun socks and it has gone from strength to strength. I also like the 5% of sales to the Special Olympics and the socks for charities (watch the video).
Oh and John has Down&amp;rsquo;s Syndrome - an amazing family!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HullCoin</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/hullcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 13:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/hullcoin/</guid>
      <description>A new digital coin has been introduced in Hull to reward people who volunteer for things. Due to regulations the receiver can cash in their coin in the form of a discount when purchasing products at certain stores.
Links
HullCoin</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphic Design for Films</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/filmgraphicdesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 08:43:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/filmgraphicdesign/</guid>
      <description>I listen to a lot of podcasts (probably 500+ a year) and one I make an extra effort to listen to every episode is 99% Invisible. It is &amp;ldquo;about all the thought that goes into the things we don’t think about — the unnoticed architecture and design that shape our world.&amp;rdquo;
I was catching up on past episodes and came across one that made me think about a whole area that I had never considered but in hindsight seems obvious that someone needs to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unexpected pricing</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/unexpectedpricing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 17:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/unexpectedpricing/</guid>
      <description>Derek Sivers highlights an interesting pricing approach in this article. He was asked to perform at a distant location. When the customer couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford the price they suggested reducing the performance time, hoping to reduce the price. Instead of doing the expected he raised his price. His reason was that they were paying for him to get to the location and then do the work where the work was the fun bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Workers</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/knowledgeworkers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 08:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/knowledgeworkers/</guid>
      <description>This is an excellent article that touches on some many areas including Amazon (again) and their structure. However the most interesting part for me is the section on the way to view knowledge workers in business:
“Knowledge-worker productivity requires that the knowledge worker is both seen and treated as an ‘asset’ rather than a ‘cost.’ It requires that knowledge workers want to work for the organization in preference to all other opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Alternative Bucket List</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/alternativebucketlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 08:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/alternativebucketlist/</guid>
      <description>I have never formally made a bucket list. Sure, there are things I would love to do and some more than others but I have never written anything down.
This article has a different way of composing this list and the focus is definitely on people. It is basically the following:
&amp;ldquo;Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re in a hospital bed, connected to a tube. You have a pen and paper in hand. Would you really list anything about visiting a foreign country or an ocean escapade?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tailor Brands</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/tailorbrands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 09:16:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/tailorbrands/</guid>
      <description>I came across a link on Product Hunt to Tailor Brands who do automatic logo creation and branding. It is great to see them still doing well. I used them for my company logo, Sentio Ventures, shortly after they started in 2014!
Links
Tailor Brands
Sentio Ventures</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain - what impact will it have?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/35blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 20:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/35blockchain/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of stories around how Blockchain could revolutionize every industry. This is a nice summary of some of the companies that are trying to make this happen and the way they are trying to make an impact.
Links
Real World Examples</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Could this revolutionize shopping?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/amazonshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 18:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/amazonshop/</guid>
      <description>Amazon just opened the first store with no cashiers or checkouts.
Using technology it has been able to do away with both of these traditional aspects of a shop and just let customers walk out, having worked out what they have purchased.
Will it revolutionize shopping? I am not sure in the short term as this is some quite impressive technology and I am not sure it scales to a normal shop or supermarket however it has the potential to really shake things up over time - or at least push the incumbent shops to think again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology: I am past it?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/pastit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 16:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/pastit/</guid>
      <description>This is an interesting post from Rob Conery, someone I&amp;rsquo;ve followed for quite some time, and his observations as he gets older about how he wonders if he is past keeping up with new technology.
I regularly get challenged with new roles and new technologies and often question myself but experience counts for a lot and life would be boring without challenges :)
Links
Modern Dev Team</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with the Hugo static site generator</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 16:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/hugo/</guid>
      <description>This blog is being powered by a static content generator called Hugo and hosted on GitHub Pages. Getting Hugo up and running was relatively easy. Download the relevant version and installation was just copying it to a folder.
Once installed, create a new site:
​ hugo new site mySite
In the site folder edit the config.toml file to change the baseUrl, the language and the title.
Use git to clone a theme from the available themes to a folder under the themes folder in your site.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>