<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ILearnt</title>
    <link>https://ilearnt.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ILearnt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 08:45:32 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ilearnt.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Explaining distributed systems</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/explainingdistributedsystems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 08:45:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/explainingdistributedsystems/</guid>
      <description>I love the way this article explains some of the key issues with designing distributed systems and how to solve them. It uses the illustration of a theme park and the rides - very clever and a fun read, which is unusual for a distributed systems article!
Links
Maximizing fun (and profit) in your distributed systems</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MacBook touchscreen for $1</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/macbooktouchscreen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 08:09:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/macbooktouchscreen/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t own, and have no intention of owning, a MacBook as I own a touchscreen Windows laptop however this approach to make it support touch is genius. They use a mirror at the top of the screen and some image processing to work out where the finger is. They can determine if the finger is actually touching the screen by whether it is touching its reflection - very clever lateral thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/just/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 21:00:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/just/</guid>
      <description>It is very easy to make assumptions about a subject you know well and others may not. You will have knowledge you have learnt over time that you perceive is so simple or obvious that others should just know it - forgetting that once you too had to learn it. This article sums it up really well with the word &amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;just&amp;rdquo;.
Links
Just</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missing payment</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/missingpayment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 08:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/missingpayment/</guid>
      <description>I was due to be paid for some work earlier this month and the payment was from a foreign bank account into my account in GBP. The payment was made two weeks ago but never turned up in my account. After numerous phone calls with my bank and a lot of help from the CFO of the company I am working for (thanks Mario) we eventually managed to locate the payment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Strategy/Bad Strategy by Richard P. Rumelt</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/goodstrategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 08:53:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/goodstrategy/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had this book a while but never got around to reading it properly. One of my colleagues at work was listening to the audio version of it and recommended it. This was an excellent read and very relevant to what is happening at the company I am working at at the moment. For me the key takeaway was that what most people call strategy is not actually strategy but vision or goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy is choice</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/privacyischoice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 08:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/privacyischoice/</guid>
      <description>A great quote from this podcast by 23andMe Co-Founder and CEO Anne Wojcicki &amp;hellip;
 &amp;ldquo;Privacy is not about not sharing, it is about choice&amp;rdquo;
 Links
Driving Discovery and Disruption</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pi</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/piday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 21:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/piday/</guid>
      <description>This page is devoted to maths and in particular pi. The answer to the second question on this page is unexpected and I love the energy the maths teacher brings to the class in the video. I had maths teachers but never one quite like this.
Links
Can you solve it? The Pi Day party starts here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four minute mile</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/fourminutemile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 17:26:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/fourminutemile/</guid>
      <description>I had never seen the original footage of Sir Roger Bannister running the first four minute mile. His narration of the race really adds to it as well.
Links
First Four Minute Mile</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Blockchain&#39; is meaningless</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/blockchainmeaningless/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 08:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/blockchainmeaningless/</guid>
      <description>There seems to be no single clean definition of what &amp;ldquo;Blockchain&amp;rdquo; actually means. There are a lot of woolly statements, several of which are clearly either wrong or too narrowly focused. This article goes into some of the different definitions and why they are wrong and then the implications of this from a business but also a legal perspective.
I personally think the definition by Mike Gault, CEO of Guardtime, is the closest:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Code Assistant</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/aicodeassistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 14:55:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/aicodeassistant/</guid>
      <description>Ubissoft have introduced a tool that &amp;ldquo;uses AI&amp;rdquo; to identify potential coding issues when the developer commits code. They claim it can detect a significant number of errors and even suggest solutions in some cases. There will always be some errors that it will not be able to identify, for example where the implementation doesn&amp;rsquo;t match the requirements, however this approach could have a significant impact on the amount of time spent debugging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blackout by Marc Elsberg</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/blackout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 21:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/blackout/</guid>
      <description>This story documents one scenario that could happen when the nightmare happens of a massive power cut across Europe. It starts with a number of threads and weaves them well together. It follows an Italian as he realizes it is a terrorist attack on the smart power meters. This destabilizes the power grid which takes down most of the grid across Europe. A second attack targets the power plants. This leads to a power cut across Europe that lasts days and the storyline of how they track down the cause and the perpetrators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the team size to deliver</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/reducingteamsize/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 18:15:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/reducingteamsize/</guid>
      <description>A project was struggling to deliver in time and the project manager resolved it by reducing the team size where the typical approach is to increase the team size. This decision was based on the overhead of communication and Brooks Law.
Links
Applying Brooks Law</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Platforms Must Listen to Developers to Grow</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/developerplatforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 21:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/developerplatforms/</guid>
      <description>This is an excellent study on why developers are so important to a platform. At the moment we are developing a platform and we have been trying to get this message across to the business side of the company. This article backs up what we have been saying.
 &amp;ldquo;This means that platform makers must listen and learn how developers want their platforms marketed to them and must work to help developers find interesting ways to solve tough problems using their platforms, he added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do crypto-currencies work?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/howdocryptocurrencieswork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 07:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/howdocryptocurrencieswork/</guid>
      <description>A very simple introduction to how Bitcoin works &amp;hellip; using a stuffed penguin!
Links
Bitcoin explained: How do crypto-currencies work?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Let Status Change The Conversation</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/statusconversations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 06:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/statusconversations/</guid>
      <description>I am probably like most people in that when I meet someone who I deem to be important the way I deal with them changes. It introduces a more reserved interaction with more careful responses.
It is something I am improving. I am now dealing with &amp;lsquo;C&amp;rsquo; level executives which in the past would have put me much more on the back foot.
Derek Sivers has written about a chat he had where he really clicked with someone and only later found out how important he could be to his life - which if he had known previously would have completely changed the way they interacted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unorthodox Leadership</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/unorthodoxleadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 06:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/unorthodoxleadership/</guid>
      <description>Steve Kerr, the coach of the Golden State Warriors basketball team, took an usual step recently by allowing his players to coach instead of him. He felt that things had become a little staid and wanted to shake things up &amp;hellip; it worked - they won by their highest margin of the season. Sometimes leadership is knowing when to step back.
Links
By Doing Something No One Expected, Golden State Warriors Coach Steve Kerr Taught a Brilliant Leadership Lesson</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaders Eat Last by Simon Sinek</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/leaderseatlast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 06:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/leaderseatlast/</guid>
      <description>I really liked Simon Sinek&amp;rsquo;s other books but didn&amp;rsquo;t get into this one as much - don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, it is still an excellent read and you can learn a lot.
The name comes from how officers in the US Marine Corp will eat last as opposed to most organisations where the leaders eat first. It covers why the best leaders think of others first and will put themselves at risk for others having created environments where they know others would do the same for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Technology Less Manipulative</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/technologymanipulative/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 08:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/technologymanipulative/</guid>
      <description>This was an excellent podcast on the ethics behind some of the decisions being made about technology today. The whole talk is excellent and thought provoking however for me one part (about 27 minutes in) stood out:
&amp;ldquo;When we think about AI we have to remember you know when you point the AI system at chess, right, first it kind of wiggles around and it makes some kind of funny looking moves and then it starts making some smart moves as it gets better and then it makes some surprisingly smart moves and then it beats Garry Kasparov.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning from terminally ill children</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/lifeandterminallyill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 07:23:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/lifeandterminallyill/</guid>
      <description>I am going to try and enjoy the small things in life and focus more on those close to me; something that is not always easy when caught up in the hustle and bustle of life.
Links
What terminally ill children taught this doctor about how to live</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marble roll</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/marbleroll/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 17:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/marbleroll/</guid>
      <description>Some people have way too much time on their hands.
Links
&amp;ldquo;Watch this marble roll adventurously through a DIY table maze&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stunning nature photographs</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/naturephotographs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 17:19:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/naturephotographs/</guid>
      <description>These nature photos are absolutely stunning. Some people have a gift for photography &amp;hellip; and I am not one of them.
Links
Winning photos from the International Garden Photographer of the Year 2018</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Your Life: How to Build a Well-Lived, Joyful Life by Bill Burnett and Dave Evans</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/designingyourlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 07:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/designingyourlife/</guid>
      <description>I was really looking forward to this book as I had listened to a podcast where they explained the ideas behind it. The two authors run a design course in Stanford that gets massively oversubscribed and has a huge impact on those who take it by looking at life as a design problem. The aim is to come up with lots of possible routes for your life that could be awesome and then design a path to achieve one of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Water Refills</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/freewater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 21:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/freewater/</guid>
      <description>This is such a simple idea and could potentially have a huge impact if it takes off - cafes and pubs filling up water bottles for free.
Links
Free Water Refill Stations: An Idea To End The Plastic Bottle Scourge</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart glasses you might actually wear</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/intelvaunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 21:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/intelvaunt/</guid>
      <description>Intel have just announced a new set of smart glasses that don&amp;rsquo;t look stupid. Admittedly the functionality is a lot more limited that other offerings however these look a lot more normal than them. It provides very limited functionality to display a small red image in the lower part of the wearers vision. Cleverly it also disappears when the user is not looking down.
They have some grand plans for it but I do question whether the limited display provides enough functionality to get users to use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancing without Sound</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/dancingwithoutsound/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 07:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/dancingwithoutsound/</guid>
      <description>My daughter loves dancing - always has done - whether it is street, contemporary or ballet. However she faces none of the challenges the dancers (and musicians) in this video face. I won&amp;rsquo;t spoil it here &amp;hellip; just watch.
Links
Dancing without sound</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TP-Link RE650</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/re650/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 21:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/re650/</guid>
      <description>I had a very unusual setup for the network for my office. The office is situated a floor above and at the opposite end of the house to where the main router is located. A fully wired connection is not an option at the moment due to concrete floors and limited access to roof voids.
Previously this meant using a wireless extender into the room above the router and then using HomePlugs to connect to the office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ma’agalim - Jane Bordeaux</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/maagalim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 07:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/maagalim/</guid>
      <description>This is a beautiful music video. Watch it all the way through and carefully watch what happens to some of the characters.
Links
Ma’agalim - Jane Bordeaux</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professionals v Amateurs</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/professional/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 15:46:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/professional/</guid>
      <description>This article defines the difference between a professional developer and an amateur as:
A professional always does everything necessary to complete a job. An amateur sometimes chooses only the fun parts.
It goes on further to say that the amateur only codes what they have been told; the professional bring &amp;ldquo;their full brain, experience and creativity&amp;rdquo;. To be professional is to go the extra mile, think about the work and deliver something that delivers what is needed (which is not necessarily what has been defined).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kubernetes Book by Nigel Poulton</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/thekubernetesbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 07:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/thekubernetesbook/</guid>
      <description>At the moment I am having to get up to speed on a bunch of technologies relating to &amp;ldquo;DevOps&amp;rdquo;. This includes Kubernetes. I borrowed this book from a colleague and read it over the course of two days commuting. It provides a very good high level overview of all the main concepts of the platform.
As an introduction, which is exactly what I needed, it was perfectly pitched however if I was going to have to get my hands dirty with using the platform in anger then there are probably better options out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When The Game Was Ours by Jackie MacMullan, Larry Bird, and Magic Johnson</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/whenthegamewasours/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 07:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/whenthegamewasours/</guid>
      <description>On 12th June 1984 I was on a family holiday in the US. We had spent three weeks travelling around Florida and then up the east coast to finally end up in Boston. During the day we had a guided tour of the city and we were told that it was game seven of the NBA finals that night between the Boston Celtics and the Los Angeles Lakers.
I was only thirteen but, possibly as it was the last night of the holiday, managed to persuade my parents that I could stay up and watch the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crazy Socks</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/crazysocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 13:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/crazysocks/</guid>
      <description>This is a great article about a small business that is growing rapidly and run with a smile on their faces. John and his dad started a business to sell crazy, fun socks and it has gone from strength to strength. I also like the 5% of sales to the Special Olympics and the socks for charities (watch the video).
Oh and John has Down&amp;rsquo;s Syndrome - an amazing family!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HullCoin</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/hullcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 13:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/hullcoin/</guid>
      <description>A new digital coin has been introduced in Hull to reward people who volunteer for things. Due to regulations the receiver can cash in their coin in the form of a discount when purchasing products at certain stores.
Links
HullCoin</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphic Design for Films</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/filmgraphicdesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 08:43:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/filmgraphicdesign/</guid>
      <description>I listen to a lot of podcasts (probably 500+ a year) and one I make an extra effort to listen to every episode is 99% Invisible. It is &amp;ldquo;about all the thought that goes into the things we don’t think about — the unnoticed architecture and design that shape our world.&amp;rdquo;
I was catching up on past episodes and came across one that made me think about a whole area that I had never considered but in hindsight seems obvious that someone needs to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unexpected pricing</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/unexpectedpricing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 17:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/unexpectedpricing/</guid>
      <description>Derek Sivers highlights an interesting pricing approach in this article. He was asked to perform at a distant location. When the customer couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford the price they suggested reducing the performance time, hoping to reduce the price. Instead of doing the expected he raised his price. His reason was that they were paying for him to get to the location and then do the work where the work was the fun bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Workers</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/knowledgeworkers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 08:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/knowledgeworkers/</guid>
      <description>This is an excellent article that touches on some many areas including Amazon (again) and their structure. However the most interesting part for me is the section on the way to view knowledge workers in business:
“Knowledge-worker productivity requires that the knowledge worker is both seen and treated as an ‘asset’ rather than a ‘cost.’ It requires that knowledge workers want to work for the organization in preference to all other opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Alternative Bucket List</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/alternativebucketlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 08:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/alternativebucketlist/</guid>
      <description>I have never formally made a bucket list. Sure, there are things I would love to do and some more than others but I have never written anything down.
This article has a different way of composing this list and the focus is definitely on people. It is basically the following:
&amp;ldquo;Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re in a hospital bed, connected to a tube. You have a pen and paper in hand. Would you really list anything about visiting a foreign country or an ocean escapade?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tailor Brands</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/tailorbrands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 09:16:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/tailorbrands/</guid>
      <description>I came across a link on Product Hunt to Tailor Brands who do automatic logo creation and branding. It is great to see them still doing well. I used them for my company logo, Sentio Ventures, shortly after they started in 2014!
Links
Tailor Brands
Sentio Ventures</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain - what impact will it have?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/35blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 20:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/35blockchain/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of stories around how Blockchain could revolutionize every industry. This is a nice summary of some of the companies that are trying to make this happen and the way they are trying to make an impact.
Links
Real World Examples</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Could this revolutionize shopping?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/amazonshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 18:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/amazonshop/</guid>
      <description>Amazon just opened the first store with no cashiers or checkouts.
Using technology it has been able to do away with both of these traditional aspects of a shop and just let customers walk out, having worked out what they have purchased.
Will it revolutionize shopping? I am not sure in the short term as this is some quite impressive technology and I am not sure it scales to a normal shop or supermarket however it has the potential to really shake things up over time - or at least push the incumbent shops to think again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology: Am I past it?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/pastit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 16:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/pastit/</guid>
      <description>This is an interesting post from Rob Conery, someone I&amp;rsquo;ve followed for quite some time, and his observations as he gets older about how he wonders if he is past keeping up with new technology.
I regularly get challenged with new roles and new technologies and often question myself but experience counts for a lot and life would be boring without challenges :)
Links
Modern Dev Team</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with the Hugo static site generator</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 16:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/hugo/</guid>
      <description>This blog is being powered by a static content generator called Hugo and hosted on GitHub Pages. Getting Hugo up and running was relatively easy. Download the relevant version and installation was just copying it to a folder.
Once installed, create a new site:
​ hugo new site mySite
In the site folder edit the config.toml file to change the baseUrl, the language and the title.
Use git to clone a theme from the available themes to a folder under the themes folder in your site.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>