<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>I learnt about ...</title>
    <link>https://ilearnt.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on I learnt about ...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2020, Mark Rainey - All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 08:12:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ilearnt.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Categories</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/categories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 12:12:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/categories/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 12:06:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/about/</guid>
      <description>The posts on this site are mainly me capturing random thoughts or things that I find interesting and have learnt something from &amp;hellip; hence the name of the site.
Maybe, if I am lucky, you will learn something from one of the posts on this site as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop and think before you buy</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/pausingbeforebuying/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 08:12:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/pausingbeforebuying/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes it is very easy to buy things just for the sake of it. We get that rush when either we bring the item home or it is delivered. It is easy to form an addiction to that feeling.
When the sales come around we might see something on offer that we think we would like - but had probably not considered before - and this is the time to take a step back and consider whether we really need it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exposing the beauty in a problem</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/beautyinaproblem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 08:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/beautyinaproblem/</guid>
      <description>I was recently reminded of this great quote:
&amp;ldquo;When I&amp;rsquo;m working on a problem, I never think about beauty. I think only how to solve the problem. But when I have finished, if the solution is not beautiful, I know it is wrong.&amp;rdquo; - R. Buckminster Fuller
Sometimes this happens when working in the world of software.
There have been occasions where I have been working on a design and the solution just seems to fall out almost naturally - and in most cases where this has happened the beauty becomes apparent in the ease and clarity that the approach can be built on and extended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fractional talent as an alternative pool of resources</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/fractionaltalent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 07:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/fractionaltalent/</guid>
      <description>At the startup I work for we used to have a full time HR person. These were in the days when the expectation was that we would have explosive growth and the company would &amp;ldquo;at least double in size every few months&amp;rdquo;. Unfortunately that is not the way it played out - we are still making good progress but have much more realistic growth plans.
And over time we realised that a full time HR person was overkill for the size of company we were so it was decided to scale down the role - a real shame as he was a really good guy and good at his job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Committing time to stand out from the crowd</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/standingout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 07:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/standingout/</guid>
      <description>There is a famous quote that asks how you eat an elephant and the answer is one bite at a time. It can be very daunting when attempting something new especially if it is potentially a large task. However it is impossible if you don&amp;rsquo;t take the first step.
(By the way, I am not advocating eating elephants - just to be clear)
Seth Godin wrote an article recently called &amp;ldquo;The 100 hour asset&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How behaviour can shape the culture</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/culturebehaviour/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 14:04:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/culturebehaviour/</guid>
      <description>Andrew Cherrie is the pastor of Home Church. In a recent sermon entitled &amp;ldquo;7 lessons from 7 years at Home Church&amp;rdquo; he gave the following quote:
The culture is shaped by the worst behaviour the leader is willing to accept
He was particularly referencing the church however it is much broader than this.
This observation has certainly shown to be the case where I have worked. Without wanting to incriminate myself, there have been some questionable decisions made by the management in the past which have meant it has been very difficult to hold others accountable for their later actions when a precedence has been set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solitude and conversations lead to great ideas</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/solitudeandconversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 13:25:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/solitudeandconversation/</guid>
      <description>There was a tweet recently by Sahil Lavingia that stated
&amp;ldquo;Great ideas come from two places: solitude and conversation.&amp;quot;
I have certainly found this to be the case.
When I was commuting into London every day I would regularly spend 30 minutes walking back from the train station. During this time I would either listen to podcasts - all sorts of subjects - or just use the time to think. This led to a whole bunch of ideas around work or potential projects or just interesting avenues to follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we recharged the team with a fallow week</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/fallowweek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 15:10:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/fallowweek/</guid>
      <description>Due to the ongoing COVID situation the team had been struggling to stay focussed and motivated. The inability to go out, the lack of change of scenery and the sameness every day has been taking its toll. To try to address this we actively encouraged them to take time off - which, given the limitations on travel, was less appealing than it normally would be.
For those unable or unwilling to take time off we decided to introduce a &amp;ldquo;fallow week&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to change your day with meeting plans</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/meetingplans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 21:05:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/meetingplans/</guid>
      <description>I recently had a day where I had about 10 different meetings - all on different subjects. I knew that I would struggle to be productive in each of them if I turned up for them unprepared and had to switch subjects each time.
To solve this I created a simple document and added a heading for each meeting. Under each heading I made a simple bullet list of everything I wanted to cover or possibly discuss in the meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When your WPF menu alignment is wrong</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/menualignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 20:50:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/menualignment/</guid>
      <description>I had a very weird problem where my menus on a WPF application were dropping down to the left instead of the normal to the right.
It turns out it is due to having a tablet setting set to right handed &amp;hellip; even though I don&amp;rsquo;t have a tablet. The answer was found on the link at the bottom of this post.
To fix it:
Press the Windows key + R and then copy/paste the following line of text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to easily implement successful remote team retrospectives</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/fullyremoteretrospectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 11:39:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/fullyremoteretrospectives/</guid>
      <description>As part of our processes we regularly hold retrospectives. We used to do this all in a room with post-it notes - a fairly traditional approach. We would set up 4 areas: Liked, Longed, Learned and Lacked and proceed to plaster post-it notes over the different sections. Once everyone had finished we would organise each section into themes and then discuss and agree actions.
Going fully remote has obviously meant we need to take a different approach and we now drive it from a shared document we create for each retrospective in Google Docs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A first encounter with sketchnoting</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/sketchnoting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 13:54:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/sketchnoting/</guid>
      <description>One of the talks I attended at the Microsoft Build conference was called &amp;ldquo;Sketchnoting 101&amp;rdquo; and given by Nitya Narasimhan. It gave a very high level view of the approach and how anyone can quickly pick it up.
Having seen the rough approach I think I have a preference for trying it electronically as it means I can make corrections and play around with layouts. It seems that the most common tool for this is Procreate however this unfortunately is limited to the Apple ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking conferences in a remote only world</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/rethinkingconferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 08:29:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/rethinkingconferences/</guid>
      <description>I recently attended the fully virtual Microsoft Build conference. There is no way I would have been able to attend the real &amp;ldquo;physical&amp;rdquo; conference due to the location, financial commitment and time required however this gave me an opportunity to benefit from something normally out of my reach.
The conference as a whole was excellent despite the limitations of not only being virtual but also mostly broadcast from homes. The idea of running each talk multiple times to suit people in different time zones was brilliant and the variety of subjects and presentation styles was great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increasing productivity using a simple magnetic whiteboard</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/magneticwhiteboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 14:24:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/magneticwhiteboard/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I work I am always jotting down things on pieces of plain paper next to me - this could be things to do, ideas, random thoughts, planning for meetings, etc.. Every week or so I do a cull of this stack of paper and then start on a new piece of paper.
Recently I bought a small whiteboard for my daughter which she uses to plan her schoolwork. It seemed to work very well for her so I thought I would give it a try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A quick fix for missing Gmail notifications on Android phones</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/gmailsyncissueonandroid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 17:39:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/gmailsyncissueonandroid/</guid>
      <description>I occasionally stop getting Gmail notifications on my Google Pixel 2XL android phone. I later find that I have a whole bunch of emails that I had missed. I am not sure what causes it however I have found a way to make it work again.
Under Settings, select Accounts and then your Google account. Once opened click on Account sync. You will be able to see when it was last synced and you will probably find that it failed a while ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fastest way to switch Gmail accounts on Android phones</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/cyclethroughgmailaccountsonandroid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 21:36:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/cyclethroughgmailaccountsonandroid/</guid>
      <description>Using Gmail on Android it is possible to support multiple email accounts. The normal way you can change which account you are looking at is by pressing on the account picture in the top right hand corner and then selecting the user.
However I found a potentially quicker approach completely by accident. If you press on the picture as before then drag down you can cycle through the email accounts one by one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally a to-do app I use ... Microsoft To Do</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/microsofttodo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 14:28:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/microsofttodo/</guid>
      <description>I have tried numerous to-do applications in the past; from the very simplest to the all-singing, all-dancing applications and they have never stuck. I used them for a week or so and realised a month later that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t used them for a while.
The Microsoft To Do application seems to have hit a sweet spot for me. I have found myself using it regularly to track both my home and my work tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet another productivity book summaries site</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/productivitybooksummaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 09:06:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/productivitybooksummaries/</guid>
      <description>I came across an excellent site for summaries of productivity books. There are a lot of sites out there that provide summaries however the quality of the video summaries is excellent and seems to be updated fairly frequently.
Links
Productivity Game</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost productivity with meeting free days</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/meetingfreedays/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 16:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/meetingfreedays/</guid>
      <description>It is very easy for your work week to become a random collection of meetings - all with different attendees and different agendas. For developers in particular this can cause a huge hit on productivity as their day becomes disjointed and they are unable to stay focussed for the longer periods they need for their work.
We started seeing this with the team I am working with. Someone would see a big chunk of free time and schedule a meeting right in the middle of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ultimate paper airplane database</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/paperairplanedatabase/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 10:44:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/paperairplanedatabase/</guid>
      <description>This site contains a collection of easy to follow designs for paper airplanes. Something for the &amp;ldquo;kids&amp;rdquo; to try.
Links
Fold &amp;lsquo;n&amp;rsquo; Fly</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A simple addition to every meeting</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/sharedmeetingdocument/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 12:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/sharedmeetingdocument/</guid>
      <description>We have a lot of remote meetings as most of our team work a significant amount of time from home. Face to face meetings are much better for some types of meetings - especially workshops and retrospectives. As the level of expected collaboration increases the more it favours face to face interactions.
We have also been far from optimal in capturing information from meetings and discussions. We have tended to capture the actions fairly well but have failed to adequately capture the &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; - i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speed up in the long term by slowing down in the short term</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/spreadingtheknowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 08:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/spreadingtheknowledge/</guid>
      <description>On most projects there is a tendency for someone involved to become the &amp;ldquo;expert&amp;rdquo; in one or more areas. As they become comfortable and more knowledgeable in an area they will naturally gravitate to picking up tasks related to it. The need to deliver as quickly as possible can also drive this as the person who knows most is likely to be the person who can do the work quickest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch an octopus dreaming</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/octopusdreaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 16:31:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/octopusdreaming/</guid>
      <description>Obviously we have no idea whether the interpretation in the video is correct however I love they way the octopus changes colour and shape as it &amp;ldquo;dreams&amp;rdquo;.
Link
Octopus Dreaming</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A remote family breakfast</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/familybreakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 11:53:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/familybreakfast/</guid>
      <description>Someone I work with mentioned that each week he takes time to have coffee with his mum. This might sound quite normal but there are two parts that stand out for me.
Firstly it is the actual act of scheduling time to do this. It is very easy in today&amp;rsquo;s world to get so busy that we forget about the important stuff. Secondly, he lives in London and his mum lives in South Africa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goggles give back sight</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/gogglesgivebacksight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 07:33:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/gogglesgivebacksight/</guid>
      <description>This short clip is pretty remarkable. A young woman lost most of her sight due to a brain tumour. All she has left is a small blurry circle in her right eye. With the use of some AR goggles and some very clever tech she was able to read for the first time in years - very moving.
Links
Goggles &amp;lsquo;give back&amp;rsquo; sight to Maisy so she can read again</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep is your superpower</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/sleepisyoursuperpower/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 07:30:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/sleepisyoursuperpower/</guid>
      <description>This is one of the scariest videos I think I have ever seen. It is not a horror movie or a thriller - it is a talk about the impact sleep has on the body and in particular the impact a lack of sleep has. This includes increasing the risk of cancer, decreased brain function and reduced immune system. I am seriously reconsidering how I &amp;ldquo;do&amp;rdquo; sleep after watching this!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Even more book summaries</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/booksummaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 07:34:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/booksummaries/</guid>
      <description>I read a lot of books - a bit less at the moment as I commute less - but still probably more than most people. However there are so many books I would like to read I can&amp;rsquo;t read them all. I still prefer to read the full book but sometimes book summaries are useful - either to get the key concepts or as a reminder of what I have previously read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tackle the difficult problems first with #MonkeyFirst</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/monkeyfirst/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 08:36:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/monkeyfirst/</guid>
      <description>I was listening to the audiobook for &amp;ldquo;Questions Are the Answer&amp;rdquo; by Hal Gregerson and it mentioned an approach used by the X lab at Alphabet nicknamed &amp;ldquo;MonkeyFirst&amp;rdquo;.
It talks about the hypothetical problem of getting a monkey to recite passages of Shakespeare while sitting at the top of a 10 foot pedestal. There is a natural tendency to start working on the pedestal. It is something we know how to do and would show progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consensus 2019 - Conference Notes</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/consensus2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 18:08:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/consensus2019/</guid>
      <description>These are my notes from attending the Consensus 2019 conference in New York - there is a good chance that some of the notes I made are incorrect.
State of Blockchain Alex Sunnarborg - Tetras Capital
  Bitmex - 10 billion volume in 24 hours
  Decentralized Finance (DeFi) has locked up &amp;gt;2% of ETH
  Blockchain developer demand up 33x
  Institutions views on digital assets</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazy programmers can be the most productive</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/lazyprogrammers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 08:07:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/lazyprogrammers/</guid>
      <description>There is often a work culture that you should be busy all the time - if you are a programmer you should always be typing and producing code. Programming is a mental process and so requires thinking. Sometimes a little thought upfront saves a lot of pain and work down the line.
The article below has a potentially controversial headline but sums this up really well. Being perceived as lazy as a programmer can actually be a good thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A clear desk helps avoid being the bottleneck</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/bottlenecks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 07:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/bottlenecks/</guid>
      <description>I really like Seth Godin&amp;rsquo;s blog - I could easily link to his posts every day - however occasionally a post really stands out for me. A recent post called Bottlenecks had an interesting observation that was a different way of thinking about them.
I worked for a company a long time ago where the person running the company insisted on everything going through them - whether it was important decisions like strategy or minor stuff like approving the purchase of paper clips!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical debt is like Tetris</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/technicaldebttetris/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 07:05:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/technicaldebttetris/</guid>
      <description>This article uses a really neat analogy with Tetris for illustrating the impact of technical debt. Leaving gaps is akin to leaving technical debt in the code base and makes subsequent changes more difficult or slower to ship.
 A buried gap in Tetris represents technical debt.
 It also points out the fact that it is called debt and so has to be paid off at some point.
 Paying down technical debt keeps you competitive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering problem solvers - not offering solutions</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/empoweringproblemsolvers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 18:10:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/empoweringproblemsolvers/</guid>
      <description>There is a natural reaction for people when faced with a problem to offer solutions. This can be especially true for managers.
The article linked below highlights this and offers an alternative approach to the situation where an employee approaches their manager with a problem. A lot of managers will immediately jump into problem solving mode and propose one or more solutions to the problem. It proposes that the role of the manager is not to solve problems, as that is what the employee was effectively employed to do, but to help others solve problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It always pays to leave well</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/leavingwell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 09:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/leavingwell/</guid>
      <description>When someone leaves a company there are two sides to it.
The first side is the way the employee behaves and handles themselves. I always aim to be professional and work hard until the moment I leave the office for the last time. I like to think that is one of the reasons my last four roles have involved word of mouth recommendations.
I have seen some people, who were excellent up to that point, almost switch off once they have announced they are leaving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The battle of real versus artificial deadlines</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/deadlinetypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 16:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/deadlinetypes/</guid>
      <description>This excellent article looks at the different types of deadlines and the impact they have. The key point for me, and not something I had seen previously defined, is the distinction between real and artificial deadlines:
 Real deadlines have a direct (and often large) economic consequence. Not meeting the deadline will seriously jeopardize some future outcome. Artificial deadlines don’t work like that. There may be an economic impact, but the link between “hitting the date” and the economic impact will be a lot more subtle and abstract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to run a planning workshop</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/planningworkshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 08:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/planningworkshop/</guid>
      <description>We have just completed a two week exercise with the whole development team to identify, design and estimate the next phase of work. It started as an organic process as we found the best way to do this and then developed into a repeatable process for the latter functionality.
Before starting on the individual breakdowns we produced a list of things to consider for everything we were estimating. This mostly consisted of a list of functional requirements like logging, testing, documentation, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Places to name things</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/namingresources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 09:22:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/namingresources/</guid>
      <description>This one is just for future reference for me that I may find useful one day - a website full of resources that may be useful for naming things.
Links
Onym</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do we really need that meeting? - the forgotten costs</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/meetingcosts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 09:22:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/meetingcosts/</guid>
      <description>We had a meeting recently with 16 people on the video conference call. Due to poor planning and technical issues it took nearly half an hour to decide to postpone the meeting. That is eight man hours wasted - a whole day of work!
This article proposes an add-on to the calendar that informs the person booking the meeting how much the meeting will effectively cost the company. Love it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The value of throwing code away</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/throwawaycode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 08:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/throwawaycode/</guid>
      <description>We had a discussion at work about &amp;ldquo;throw away&amp;rdquo; code. One of our developers was very against developing any code that would be thrown away afterwards. He referred to this as a waste. In my view sometimes the biggest gain can be in developing code that is meant to be thrown away. It can be used to try things and, more importantly, learn things that can shape the code that is kept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From 5 whys to why now?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/whynow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 14:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/whynow/</guid>
      <description>I have used the &amp;ldquo;5 whys&amp;rdquo; approach multiple times to get to the root of some question. This article advocates adding a time dimension to the decision. Not only should we consider why we are doing something, we should also consider why we are doing something at a specific point in time. It also twists this around and suggests we should consider &amp;ldquo;What is the danger of not doing this right now?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to identify real gurus and experts</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/gurusandexperts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 08:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/gurusandexperts/</guid>
      <description>This is an old post (March 2009) that someone retweeted but still holds true on how to work out if an expert is really an expert. It also is a guide how not to fall into common traps that so-called experts fall into.
Links
How to Call Bullshit on a Guru or Expert</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating 3D animations from a 2D photo</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/3dfrom2d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 10:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/3dfrom2d/</guid>
      <description>This is a pretty amazing demonstration of animating an aspect of a 2d photo. This even includes pulling out bodies and animating them moving away from their original scene.
If we can simulate video in this way then can we ever still believe video as proof of what has happened?
Links
Photo Wake-Up: 3D Character Animation from a Single Photo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Mirror - technology ethics and can it be used for wrong?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/blackmirrortesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 08:15:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/blackmirrortesting/</guid>
      <description>Nearly every technology that has been developed has been used for both good and bad. Developments that look like they could have a massive impact on civilization have usually also spun off a side effect that has a detrimental effect. This could be the latest technologies such as genetic engineering and artificial intelligence or older technologies such as the automobile.
This article discusses using an exercise during the development of the technology to identify these wrong uses and how/if they can be alleviated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antilibrary - should I finish the book I am reading?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/antilibrary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 11:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/antilibrary/</guid>
      <description>I read a lot of books and once I start reading a book I normally finish it. This article proposes that it may be more valuable to have a bunch of books that are unread. Not sure I completely buy in to the proposition that &amp;ldquo;Read books are far less valuable than unread ones&amp;rdquo; however maybe I won&amp;rsquo;t feel so guilty buying a book and then leaving it unread.
Links</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Github SSH</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/githubssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 14:00:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/githubssh/</guid>
      <description>Just a reminder of the starting point for setting up SSH with Github so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to keep looking for it each time.
Links
Connecting to GitHub with SSH</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git - what to do when it goes wrong</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/flightrulesforgit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 16:45:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/flightrulesforgit/</guid>
      <description>This has a great summary of what to do when things go wrong when using Git. Added here so I know where to look in moments of panic.
Links
Flight Rules for Git</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sometimes to learn you also need to do</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/learningwithoutdoing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 17:08:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/learningwithoutdoing/</guid>
      <description>I am back on the learning Scala trail and it is clear that just reading books and articles or watching videos won&amp;rsquo;t cut it. It needs to be hands-on coding.
This article highlights that some skills cannot be learnt without actual doing.
Links
Learning without doing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The secret history of Ctrl&#43;Alt&#43;Del</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/altcontroldelete/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 17:04:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/altcontroldelete/</guid>
      <description>The background to why the famous &amp;ldquo;three finger salute&amp;rdquo; was chosen to be so difficult to do.
Links
The secret history of Ctrl+Alt+Del</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scala &#43; Sbt &#43; Docker quickly</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/scaladocker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 07:42:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/scaladocker/</guid>
      <description>I am currently starting to learn Scala (to add to a myriad of other languages I have programmed in over my career). We are also in the process of &amp;ldquo;dockerizing&amp;rdquo; our application. So I wanted to try for myself getting a simple Scala application running in Docker.
This page has a very simple guide to getting a &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; application up and running.
Links
Getting Started With Docker, Scala &amp;amp; Sbt</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abandoning the baggage of Agile</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/developersshouldabandonagile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 06:46:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/developersshouldabandonagile/</guid>
      <description>I have worked with various flavours of &amp;ldquo;Agile&amp;rdquo; over numerous years. These have ranged from the very formal where everything is done by the book to more ad-hoc versions where different parts are cherry picked or in most cases done because people think they should be done.
What is clear is that &amp;ldquo;Agile&amp;rdquo; has become more about the processes than about the results and the actual aims of the original manifesto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abolish performance reviews</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/abolishperformancereviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 06:41:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/abolishperformancereviews/</guid>
      <description>I have never been a fan of performance reviews. It may have been down to the way they were implemented at the places I worked however they never seemed to achieve what they were set out to do. The review would usually consist of going over the &amp;ldquo;achievements&amp;rdquo; for the past period and then setting a bunch of artificial goals for the next period. The only time these new goals were actually consulted was in the run up to the next review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel the world with the geographic game - GeoGuessr</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/geoguessr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 07:17:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/geoguessr/</guid>
      <description>This is a very simple idea for a quiz. It drops you in a random place somewhere in the world and you use Google StreetView to work out where it is. If you are lucky you end up in a town or city, sometimes you end up in the middle of nowhere. It is amazing how much you can work out by looking at the flora or a random signpost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The legacy vulnerability of the Internet</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/networkdevelopments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 06:51:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/networkdevelopments/</guid>
      <description>This article documents developments over the last ten years at all layers of the network stack. It also highlights how vulnerable the current Internet is.
Links
Another ten years later</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A simple change can lead to a big Impact</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/disposablecups/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 17:35:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/disposablecups/</guid>
      <description>A simple change in message can lead to a big impact.
Without changing the price of the drink, the University of Winchester reduced the number of disposal cups used in a year by 34K. This was achieved by saying there was a &amp;ldquo;25p penalty&amp;rdquo; for using a disposable cup rather than a &amp;ldquo;25p discount&amp;rdquo; for using a reusable one.
Links
Plastic coffee cup waste is being cut by a simple change</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In a distributed system ... there is no now</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/thereisnonow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 07:41:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/thereisnonow/</guid>
      <description>This paper is a discussion around the issues faced by distributed systems when dealing with time, ordering and failures. This is particularly relevant with the work I am doing at the moment designing a very large distributed system that will need to scale massively.
It is remarkably readable and illustrates key issues and limitations in the field. It has already got me researching other areas mentioned in the paper.
Links</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Hitchhiker’s Guide to Consensus Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/consensusalgorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 07:18:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/consensusalgorithms/</guid>
      <description>This is a summary of a number of consensus algorithms currently being used in the Blockchain space. The most common at the moment is Proof of Work however this is slowly being replaced by other approaches that are more performant and don&amp;rsquo;t use all the Earth&amp;rsquo;s energy.
Links
A Hitchhiker’s Guide to Consensus Algorithms</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REST API Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/restapiguidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 08:15:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/restapiguidelines/</guid>
      <description>This is here for future reference - a very good set of guidelines for REST APIs.
Links
Zalando RESTful API and Event Scheme Guidelines</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The accelerated pace of image processing developments</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/imageprocessingdevelopments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 07:19:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/imageprocessingdevelopments/</guid>
      <description>There are some amazing things happening with image processing at the moment. I remember my graphics class at university 25 years ago and the primitive, by comparison to now, image processing algorithms we had to code. Oh how things have moved on.
The first link below is some incredible work to make very low light images intelligible. The example results are quite incredible - making a viewable image out of an image that looks completely dark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A personal link to &#39;The Mother Of All Demos&#39;</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/motherofalldemos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 07:47:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/motherofalldemos/</guid>
      <description>There is a video of a demonstration given by Doug Engelbart in 1968 which is commonly referred to as &amp;ldquo;The Mother Of All Demos&amp;rdquo;. In the demo, he demonstrates a lot of technologies for the first time together that are common place today and some which we haven&amp;rsquo;t even achieved properly now:
 windows hypertext graphics efficient navigation and command input video conferencing the computer mouse word processing dynamic file linking revision control collaborative real-time editor (collaborative work)  One of the demonstrations that is particularly of interest to me is the chorded keyboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working from home boosts productivity</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/workingfromhomeboost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 07:13:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/workingfromhomeboost/</guid>
      <description>I am fortunate with my current role that I am able to work 2-3 days per week from home. This saves me about 2.5 hours of commuting time per day as well as about £2000 per year.
A new study from Stanford University has shown that working from home can increase productivity significantly. There is a small proviso that working 100% of the time from home can also have a detrimental effect as it can lead to isolation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The bosses who change our lives</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/thebossesweremember/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 07:41:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/thebossesweremember/</guid>
      <description>I have been very fortunate in my career to have some exceptional bosses that have had a massive impact on my career.
Kim Ho
When I came out of university it was in the middle of a recession. Despite coming second in my whole year I had to send my CV out to 45 places before I got a single response. Fortunately I got the role and I have never been out of work since (in over 25 years).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Armada by Ernest Cline</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/armada/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 07:00:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/armada/</guid>
      <description>Took me a little while to get into this book. It starts out in a school where a pupil spots a spaceship from his favourite video game. This then moves on to it being a precursor to an invasion by the aliens from the video game and the game itself was actually put together as training so the players could pilot drones in the war. A slightly surreal concept but pretty well executed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero to One by Peter Thiel</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/zerotoone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 07:00:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/zerotoone/</guid>
      <description>I had read a lot of good things about this book and it had sat on my Kindle for a long time. Really enjoyed the first half of the book but thought the second half was more focused on things that weren&amp;rsquo;t relevant to me. There were some statements made that were clearly opinions but were stated as facts. Overall a bit disappointing.
Links
Zero To One</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The unseen impact of the little trade-offs</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/thelittletradeoffs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 08:36:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/thelittletradeoffs/</guid>
      <description>I found this article to be a very astute observation that it can be all the &amp;ldquo;little trade-offs&amp;rdquo; that can add up to cause issues. The article highlights it from the perspective of a leader who can make small decisions, usually around putting something off or taking a short cut, that can add up to impact their work and those around them.
I have also seen this with technical projects. Sometimes small decisions can cascade through a project and cause massive problems later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An entrancing dance with just the hands</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/dancingwithhands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 07:51:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/dancingwithhands/</guid>
      <description>My daughter loves dancing. She was entranced by this (so was I). The effort this must have taken to choreograph and the level of control between both the dancers is impressive.
Links
Dancing with hands</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The amazing evolution of the English alphabet</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/englishalphabet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 08:29:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/englishalphabet/</guid>
      <description>A simple chart showing how the English alphabet evolved and how we ended up with what we have. It is particularly interesting how the Roman alphabet changed to become the English alphabet.
Links
Evolution of the English alphabet</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making the explanation of distributed systems fun</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/explainingdistributedsystems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 08:45:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/explainingdistributedsystems/</guid>
      <description>I love the way this article explains some of the key issues with designing distributed systems and how to solve them. It uses the illustration of a theme park and the rides - very clever and a fun read, which is unusual for a distributed systems article!
Links
Maximizing fun (and profit) in your distributed systems</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A MacBook touchscreen for only $1</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/macbooktouchscreen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 08:09:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/macbooktouchscreen/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t own, and have no intention of owning, a MacBook as I own a touchscreen Windows laptop however this approach to make it support touch is genius. They use a mirror at the top of the screen and some image processing to work out where the finger is. They can determine if the finger is actually touching the screen by whether it is touching its reflection - very clever lateral thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is &#39;just&#39; ...</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/just/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 21:00:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/just/</guid>
      <description>It is very easy to make assumptions about a subject you know well and others may not. You will have knowledge you have learnt over time that you perceive is so simple or obvious that others should just know it - forgetting that once you too had to learn it. This article sums it up really well with the word &amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;just&amp;rdquo;.
Links
Just</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to track down a missing international payment</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/missingpayment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 08:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/missingpayment/</guid>
      <description>I was due to be paid for some work earlier this month and the payment was from a foreign bank account into my account in GBP. The payment was made two weeks ago but never turned up in my account. After numerous phone calls with my bank and a lot of help from the CFO of the company I am working for (thanks Mario) we eventually managed to locate the payment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Strategy/Bad Strategy by Richard P. Rumelt</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/goodstrategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 08:53:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/goodstrategy/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had this book a while but never got around to reading it properly. One of my colleagues at work was listening to the audio version of it and recommended it. This was an excellent read and very relevant to what is happening at the company I am working at at the moment. For me the key takeaway was that what most people call strategy is not actually strategy but vision or goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy should be our choice</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/privacyischoice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 08:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/privacyischoice/</guid>
      <description>A great quote from this podcast by 23andMe Co-Founder and CEO Anne Wojcicki &amp;hellip;
 &amp;ldquo;Privacy is not about not sharing, it is about choice&amp;rdquo;
 Links
Driving Discovery and Disruption</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pi</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/piday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 21:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/piday/</guid>
      <description>This page is devoted to maths and in particular pi. The answer to the second question on this page is unexpected and I love the energy the maths teacher brings to the class in the video. I had some okay maths teachers but never one quite like this.
Links
Can you solve it? The Pi Day party starts here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ultimate broken mental barrier - the four minute mile</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/fourminutemile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 17:26:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/fourminutemile/</guid>
      <description>I had never seen the original footage of Sir Roger Bannister running the first four minute mile. His narration of the race really adds to it as well.
Links
First Four Minute Mile</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The term &#39;Blockchain&#39; is meaningless</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/blockchainmeaningless/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 08:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/blockchainmeaningless/</guid>
      <description>There seems to be no single clean definition of what &amp;ldquo;Blockchain&amp;rdquo; actually means. There are a lot of woolly statements, several of which are clearly either wrong or too narrowly focused. This article goes into some of the different definitions and why they are wrong and then the implications of this from a business but also a legal perspective.
I personally think the definition by Mike Gault, CEO of Guardtime, is the closest:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using AI to find code problems</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/aicodeassistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 14:55:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/aicodeassistant/</guid>
      <description>Ubissoft have introduced a tool that &amp;ldquo;uses AI&amp;rdquo; to identify potential coding issues when the developer commits code. They claim it can detect a significant number of errors and even suggest solutions in some cases. There will always be some errors that it will not be able to identify, for example where the implementation doesn&amp;rsquo;t match the requirements, however this approach could have a significant impact on the amount of time spent debugging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blackout by Marc Elsberg</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/blackout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 21:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/blackout/</guid>
      <description>This story documents one scenario that could happen when the nightmare happens of a massive power cut across Europe. It starts with a number of threads and weaves them well together. It follows an Italian as he realizes it is a terrorist attack on the smart power meters. This destabilizes the power grid which takes down most of the grid across Europe. A second attack targets the power plants. This leads to a power cut across Europe that lasts days and the storyline of how they track down the cause and the perpetrators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the team size to deliver</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/reducingteamsize/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 18:15:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/reducingteamsize/</guid>
      <description>A project was struggling to deliver in time and the project manager resolved it by reducing the team size where the typical approach is to increase the team size. This decision was based on the overhead of communication and Brooks Law.
Links
Applying Brooks Law</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer platforms must listen to developers in order to grow</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/developerplatforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 21:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/developerplatforms/</guid>
      <description>This is an excellent study on why developers are so important to a platform. At the moment we are developing a platform and we have been trying to get this message across to the business side of the company. This article backs up what we have been saying.
 &amp;ldquo;This means that platform makers must listen and learn how developers want their platforms marketed to them and must work to help developers find interesting ways to solve tough problems using their platforms, he added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do crypto-currencies work?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/howdocryptocurrencieswork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 07:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/howdocryptocurrencieswork/</guid>
      <description>A very simple introduction to how Bitcoin works &amp;hellip; using a stuffed penguin!
Links
Bitcoin explained: How do crypto-currencies work?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t let status change the conversation</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/statusconversations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 06:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/statusconversations/</guid>
      <description>I am probably like most people in that when I meet someone who I deem to be important the way I deal with them changes. It introduces a more reserved interaction with more careful responses.
It is something I am improving. I am now dealing with &amp;lsquo;C&amp;rsquo; level executives which in the past would have put me much more on the back foot.
Derek Sivers has written about a chat he had where he really clicked with someone and only later found out how important he could be to his life - which if he had known previously would have completely changed the way they interacted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unorthodox leadership by letting others drive</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/unorthodoxleadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 06:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/unorthodoxleadership/</guid>
      <description>Steve Kerr, the coach of the Golden State Warriors basketball team, took an usual step recently by allowing his players to coach instead of him. He felt that things had become a little staid and wanted to shake things up &amp;hellip; it worked - they won by their highest margin of the season. Sometimes leadership is knowing when to step back.
Links
By Doing Something No One Expected, Golden State Warriors Coach Steve Kerr Taught a Brilliant Leadership Lesson</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaders Eat Last by Simon Sinek</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/leaderseatlast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 06:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/leaderseatlast/</guid>
      <description>I really liked Simon Sinek&amp;rsquo;s other books but didn&amp;rsquo;t get into this one as much - don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, it is still an excellent read and you can learn a lot.
The name comes from how officers in the US Marine Corp will eat last as opposed to most organisations where the leaders eat first. It covers why the best leaders think of others first and will put themselves at risk for others having created environments where they know others would do the same for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making technology less manipulative</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/technologymanipulative/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 08:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/technologymanipulative/</guid>
      <description>This was an excellent podcast on the ethics behind some of the decisions being made about technology today. The whole talk is excellent and thought provoking however for me one part (about 27 minutes in) stood out:
 &amp;ldquo;When we think about AI we have to remember you know when you point the AI system at chess, right, first it kind of wiggles around and it makes some kind of funny looking moves and then it starts making some smart moves as it gets better and then it makes some surprisingly smart moves and then it beats Garry Kasparov.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning from terminally ill children</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/lifeandterminallyill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 07:23:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/lifeandterminallyill/</guid>
      <description>I am going to try and enjoy the small things in life and focus more on those close to me; something that is not always easy when caught up in the hustle and bustle of life.
Links
What terminally ill children taught this doctor about how to live</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The DIY table maze marble roll</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/marbleroll/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 17:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/marbleroll/</guid>
      <description>Some people have way too much time on their hands.
Links
&amp;ldquo;Watch this marble roll adventurously through a DIY table maze&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stunning nature photographs</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/naturephotographs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 17:19:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/naturephotographs/</guid>
      <description>These nature photos are absolutely stunning. Some people have a gift for photography &amp;hellip; and I am not one of them.
Links
Winning photos from the International Garden Photographer of the Year 2018</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Your Life: How to Build a Well-Lived, Joyful Life by Bill Burnett and Dave Evans</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/designingyourlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 07:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/designingyourlife/</guid>
      <description>I was really looking forward to this book as I had listened to a podcast where they explained the ideas behind it. The two authors run a design course in Stanford that gets massively oversubscribed and has a huge impact on those who take it by looking at life as a design problem. The aim is to come up with lots of possible routes for your life that could be awesome and then design a path to achieve one of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart glasses you might actually wear</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/intelvaunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 21:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/intelvaunt/</guid>
      <description>Intel have just announced a new set of smart glasses that don&amp;rsquo;t look stupid. Admittedly the functionality is a lot more limited that other offerings however these look a lot more normal than them. It provides very limited functionality to display a small red image in the lower part of the wearers vision. Cleverly it also disappears when the user is not looking down.
They have some grand plans for it but I do question whether the limited display provides enough functionality to get users to use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The simple idea of free water refills</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/freewater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 21:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/freewater/</guid>
      <description>This is such a simple idea and could potentially have a huge impact if it takes off - cafes and pubs filling up water bottles for free.
Links
Free Water Refill Stations: An Idea To End The Plastic Bottle Scourge</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancing without sound</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/dancingwithoutsound/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 07:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/dancingwithoutsound/</guid>
      <description>My daughter loves dancing - always has done - whether it is street, contemporary or ballet. However she faces none of the challenges the dancers (and musicians) in this video face. I won&amp;rsquo;t spoil it here &amp;hellip; just watch.
Links
Dancing without sound</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending a wifi network with a TP-Link RE650</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/re650/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 21:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/re650/</guid>
      <description>I had a very unusual setup for the network for my office. The office is situated a floor above and at the opposite end of the house to where the main router is located. A fully wired connection is not an option at the moment due to concrete floors and limited access to roof voids.
Previously this meant using a wireless extender into the room above the router and then using HomePlugs to connect to the office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ma’agalim - Jane Bordeaux</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/maagalim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 07:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/maagalim/</guid>
      <description>This is a beautiful music video. Watch it all the way through and carefully watch what happens to some of the characters.
Links
Ma’agalim - Jane Bordeaux</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professionals do everything necessary - not just the fun bits</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/professional/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 15:46:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/professional/</guid>
      <description>This article defines the difference between a professional developer and an amateur as:
A professional always does everything necessary to complete a job. An amateur sometimes chooses only the fun parts.
It goes on further to say that the amateur only codes what they have been told; the professional bring &amp;ldquo;their full brain, experience and creativity&amp;rdquo;. To be professional is to go the extra mile, think about the work and deliver something that delivers what is needed (which is not necessarily what has been defined).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kubernetes Book by Nigel Poulton</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/thekubernetesbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 07:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/thekubernetesbook/</guid>
      <description>At the moment I am having to get up to speed on a bunch of technologies relating to &amp;ldquo;DevOps&amp;rdquo;. This includes Kubernetes. I borrowed this book from a colleague and read it over the course of two days commuting. It provides a very good high level overview of all the main concepts of the platform.
As an introduction, which is exactly what I needed, it was perfectly pitched however if I was going to have to get my hands dirty with using the platform in anger then there are probably better options out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When The Game Was Ours by Jackie MacMullan, Larry Bird, and Magic Johnson</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/whenthegamewasours/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 07:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/whenthegamewasours/</guid>
      <description>On 12th June 1984 I was on a family holiday in the US. We had spent three weeks travelling around Florida and then up the east coast to finally end up in Boston. During the day we had a guided tour of the city and we were told that it was game seven of the NBA finals that night between the Boston Celtics and the Los Angeles Lakers.
I was only thirteen but, possibly as it was the last night of the holiday, managed to persuade my parents that I could stay up and watch the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rewarding the act of volunteering</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/hullcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 13:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/hullcoin/</guid>
      <description>A new digital coin has been introduced in Hull to reward people who volunteer for things. Due to regulations the receiver can cash in their coin in the form of a discount when purchasing products at certain stores.
Links
HullCoin</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using crazy socks to make an impact</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/crazysocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 13:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/crazysocks/</guid>
      <description>This is a great article about a small business that is growing rapidly and run with a smile on their faces. John and his dad started a business to sell crazy, fun socks and it has gone from strength to strength. I also like the 5% of sales to the Special Olympics and the socks for charities (watch the video).
Oh and John has Down&amp;rsquo;s Syndrome - an amazing family!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The little things in films can make a big difference</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/filmgraphicdesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 08:43:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/filmgraphicdesign/</guid>
      <description>I listen to a lot of podcasts (probably 500+ a year) and one I make an extra effort to listen to every episode is 99% Invisible. It is &amp;ldquo;about all the thought that goes into the things we don’t think about — the unnoticed architecture and design that shape our world.&amp;rdquo;
I was catching up on past episodes and came across one that made me think about a whole area that I had never considered but in hindsight seems obvious that someone needs to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surprising the customer with unexpected pricing</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/unexpectedpricing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 17:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/unexpectedpricing/</guid>
      <description>Derek Sivers highlights an interesting pricing approach in this article. He was asked to perform at a distant location. When the customer couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford the price they suggested reducing the performance time, hoping to reduce the price. Instead of doing the expected he raised his price. His reason was that they were paying for him to get to the location and then do the work where the work was the fun bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge workers are assets not costs</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/knowledgeworkers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 08:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/knowledgeworkers/</guid>
      <description>This is an excellent article that touches on some many areas including Amazon (again) and their structure. However the most interesting part for me is the section on the way to view knowledge workers in business:
“Knowledge-worker productivity requires that the knowledge worker is both seen and treated as an ‘asset’ rather than a ‘cost.’ It requires that knowledge workers want to work for the organization in preference to all other opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The alternative bucket list approach to life</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/alternativebucketlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 08:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/alternativebucketlist/</guid>
      <description>I have never formally made a bucket list. Sure, there are things I would love to do and some more than others but I have never written anything down.
This article has a different way of composing this list and the focus is definitely on people. It is basically the following:
&amp;ldquo;Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re in a hospital bed, connected to a tube. You have a pen and paper in hand. Would you really list anything about visiting a foreign country or an ocean escapade?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking the pain out of logo design with Tailor Brands</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/tailorbrands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 09:16:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/tailorbrands/</guid>
      <description>I came across a link on Product Hunt to Tailor Brands who do automatic logo creation and branding. It is great to see them still doing well. I used them for my company logo, Sentio Ventures, shortly after they started in 2014!
Links
Tailor Brands
Sentio Ventures</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain - what impact will it have?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/35blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 20:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/35blockchain/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of stories around how Blockchain could revolutionize every industry. This is a nice summary of some of the companies that are trying to make this happen and the way they are trying to make an impact.
Links
Real World Examples</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Could Amazon revolutionize the shopping experience?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/amazonshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 18:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/amazonshop/</guid>
      <description>Amazon just opened the first store with no cashiers or checkouts.
Using technology it has been able to do away with both of these traditional aspects of a shop and just let customers walk out, having worked out what they have purchased.
Will it revolutionize shopping? I am not sure in the short term as this is some quite impressive technology and I am not sure it scales to a normal shop or supermarket however it has the potential to really shake things up over time - or at least push the incumbent shops to think again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology - Am I past it?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/pastit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 16:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/pastit/</guid>
      <description>This is an interesting post from Rob Conery, someone I&amp;rsquo;ve followed for quite some time, and his observations as he gets older about how he wonders if he is past keeping up with new technology.
I regularly get challenged with new roles and new technologies and often question myself but experience counts for a lot and life would be boring without challenges :)
Links
Modern Dev Team</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with the Hugo static site generator</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 16:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/hugo/</guid>
      <description>This blog is being powered by a static content generator called Hugo and hosted on GitHub Pages. Getting Hugo up and running was relatively easy. Download the relevant version and installation was just copying it to a folder.
Once installed, create a new site:
​	hugo new site mySite
In the site folder edit the config.toml file to change the baseUrl, the language and the title.
Use git to clone a theme from the available themes to a folder under the themes folder in your site.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>