<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>business on I learnt about ...</title>
    <link>https://ilearnt.com/categories/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in business on I learnt about ...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 08:29:58 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ilearnt.com/categories/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Conferences</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/rethinkingconferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 08:29:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/rethinkingconferences/</guid>
      <description>I recently attended the fully virtual Microsoft Build conference. There is no way I would have been able to attend the real &amp;ldquo;physical&amp;rdquo; conference due to the location, financial commitment and time required however this gave me an opportunity to benefit from something normally out of my reach.
The conference as a whole was excellent despite the limitations of not only being virtual but also mostly broadcast from homes. The idea of running each talk multiple times to suit people in different time zones was brilliant and the variety of subjects and presentation styles was great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productivity Book Summaries</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/productivitybooksummaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 09:06:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/productivitybooksummaries/</guid>
      <description>I came across an excellent site for summaries of productivity books. There are a lot of sites out there that provide summaries however the quality of the video summaries is excellent and seems to be updated fairly frequently.
Links
Productivity Game</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting Free Days</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/meetingfreedays/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 16:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/meetingfreedays/</guid>
      <description>It is very easy for your work week to become a random collection of meetings - all with different attendees and different agendas. For developers in particular this can cause a huge hit on productivity as their day becomes disjointed and they are unable to stay focussed for the longer periods they need for their work.
We started seeing this with the team I am working with. Someone would see a big chunk of free time and schedule a meeting right in the middle of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shared Meeting Document</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/sharedmeetingdocument/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 12:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/sharedmeetingdocument/</guid>
      <description>We have a lot of remote meetings as most of our team work a significant amount of time from home. Face to face meetings are much better for some types of meetings - especially workshops and retrospectives. As the level of expected collaboration increases the more it favours face to face interactions.
We have also been far from optimal in capturing information from meetings and discussions. We have tended to capture the actions fairly well but have failed to adequately capture the &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; - i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spreading The Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/spreadingtheknowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 08:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/spreadingtheknowledge/</guid>
      <description>On most projects there is a tendency for someone involved to become the &amp;ldquo;expert&amp;rdquo; in one or more areas. As they become comfortable and more knowledgeable in an area they will naturally gravitate to picking up tasks related to it. The need to deliver as quickly as possible can also drive this as the person who knows most is likely to be the person who can do the work quickest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#MonkeyFirst</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/monkeyfirst/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 08:36:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/monkeyfirst/</guid>
      <description>I was listening to the audiobook for &amp;ldquo;Questions Are the Answer&amp;rdquo; by Hal Gregerson and it mentioned an approach used by the X lab at Alphabet nicknamed &amp;ldquo;MonkeyFirst&amp;rdquo;.
It talks about the hypothetical problem of getting a monkey to recite passages of Shakespeare while sitting at the top of a 10 foot pedestal. There is a natural tendency to start working on the pedestal. It is something we know how to do and would show progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consensus 2019 - Conference Notes</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/consensus2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 18:08:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/consensus2019/</guid>
      <description>These are my notes from attending the Consensus 2019 conference in New York - there is a good chance that some of the notes I made are incorrect.
State of Blockchain Alex Sunnarborg - Tetras Capital
  Bitmex - 10 billion volume in 24 hours
  Decentralized Finance (DeFi) has locked up &amp;gt;2% of ETH
  Blockchain developer demand up 33x
  Institutions views on digital assets</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering Problem Solvers</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/empoweringproblemsolvers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 18:10:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/empoweringproblemsolvers/</guid>
      <description>There is a natural reaction for people when faced with a problem to offer solutions. This can be especially true for managers.
The article linked below highlights this and offers an alternative approach to the situation where an employee approaches their manager with a problem. A lot of managers will immediately jump into problem solving mode and propose one or more solutions to the problem. It proposes that the role of the manager is not to solve problems, as that is what the employee was effectively employed to do, but to help others solve problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Well</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/leavingwell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 09:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/leavingwell/</guid>
      <description>When someone leaves a company there are two sides to it.
The first side is the way the employee behaves and handles themselves. I always aim to be professional and work hard until the moment I leave the office for the last time. I like to think that is one of the reasons my last four roles have involved word of mouth recommendations.
I have seen some people, who were excellent up to that point, almost switch off once they have announced they are leaving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real v Artificial Deadlines</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/deadlinetypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 16:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/deadlinetypes/</guid>
      <description>This excellent article looks at the different types of deadlines and the impact they have. The key point for me, and not something I had seen previously defined, is the distinction between real and artificial deadlines:
 Real deadlines have a direct (and often large) economic consequence. Not meeting the deadline will seriously jeopardize some future outcome. Artificial deadlines don’t work like that. There may be an economic impact, but the link between “hitting the date” and the economic impact will be a lot more subtle and abstract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning Workshop</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/planningworkshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 08:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/planningworkshop/</guid>
      <description>We have just completed a two week exercise with the whole development team to identify, design and estimate the next phase of work. It started as an organic process as we found the best way to do this and then developed into a repeatable process for the latter functionality.
Before starting on the individual breakdowns we produced a list of things to consider for everything we were estimating. This mostly consisted of a list of functional requirements like logging, testing, documentation, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naming Resources</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/namingresources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 09:22:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/namingresources/</guid>
      <description>This one is just for future reference for me that I may find useful one day - a website full of resources that may be useful for naming things.
Links
Onym</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meeting Costs</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/meetingcosts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 09:22:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/meetingcosts/</guid>
      <description>We had a meeting recently with 16 people on the video conference call. Due to poor planning and technical issues it took nearly half an hour to decide to postpone the meeting. That is eight man hours wasted - a whole day of work!
This article proposes an add-on to the calendar that informs the person booking the meeting how much the meeting will effectively cost the company. Love it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Now?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/whynow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 14:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/whynow/</guid>
      <description>I have used the &amp;ldquo;5 whys&amp;rdquo; approach multiple times to get to the root of some question. This article advocates adding a time dimension to the decision. Not only should we consider why we are doing something, we should also consider why we are doing something at a specific point in time. It also twists this around and suggests we should consider &amp;ldquo;What is the danger of not doing this right now?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gurus and Experts</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/gurusandexperts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 08:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/gurusandexperts/</guid>
      <description>This is an old post (March 2009) that someone retweeted but still holds true on how to work out if an expert is really an expert. It also is a guide how not to fall into common traps that so-called experts fall into.
Links
How to Call Bullshit on a Guru or Expert</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abolish Performance Reviews</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/abolishperformancereviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 06:41:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/abolishperformancereviews/</guid>
      <description>I have never been a fan of performance reviews. It may have been down to the way they were implemented at the places I worked however they never seemed to achieve what they were set out to do. The review would usually consist of going over the &amp;ldquo;achievements&amp;rdquo; for the past period and then setting a bunch of artificial goals for the next period. The only time these new goals were actually consulted was in the run up to the next review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working From Home Boosts Productivity</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/workingfromhomeboost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 07:13:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/workingfromhomeboost/</guid>
      <description>I am fortunate with my current role that I am able to work 2-3 days per week from home. This saves me about 2.5 hours of commuting time per day as well as about £2000 per year.
A new study from Stanford University has shown that working from home can increase productivity significantly. There is a small proviso that working 100% of the time from home can also have a detrimental effect as it can lead to isolation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bosses We Remember</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/thebossesweremember/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 07:41:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/thebossesweremember/</guid>
      <description>I have been very fortunate in my career to have some exceptional bosses that have had a massive impact on my career.
Kim Ho
When I came out of university it was in the middle of a recession. Despite coming second in my whole year I had to send my CV out to 45 places before I got a single response. Fortunately I got the role and I have never been out of work since (in over 25 years).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Little Trade-Offs</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/thelittletradeoffs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 08:36:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/thelittletradeoffs/</guid>
      <description>I found this article to be a very astute observation that it can be all the &amp;ldquo;little trade-offs&amp;rdquo; that can add up to cause issues. The article highlights it from the perspective of a leader who can make small decisions, usually around putting something off or taking a short cut, that can add up to impact their work and those around them.
I have also seen this with technical projects. Sometimes small decisions can cascade through a project and cause massive problems later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the team size to deliver</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/reducingteamsize/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 18:15:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/reducingteamsize/</guid>
      <description>A project was struggling to deliver in time and the project manager resolved it by reducing the team size where the typical approach is to increase the team size. This decision was based on the overhead of communication and Brooks Law.
Links
Applying Brooks Law</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unorthodox Leadership</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/unorthodoxleadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 06:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/unorthodoxleadership/</guid>
      <description>Steve Kerr, the coach of the Golden State Warriors basketball team, took an usual step recently by allowing his players to coach instead of him. He felt that things had become a little staid and wanted to shake things up &amp;hellip; it worked - they won by their highest margin of the season. Sometimes leadership is knowing when to step back.
Links
By Doing Something No One Expected, Golden State Warriors Coach Steve Kerr Taught a Brilliant Leadership Lesson</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crazy Socks</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/crazysocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 13:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/crazysocks/</guid>
      <description>This is a great article about a small business that is growing rapidly and run with a smile on their faces. John and his dad started a business to sell crazy, fun socks and it has gone from strength to strength. I also like the 5% of sales to the Special Olympics and the socks for charities (watch the video).
Oh and John has Down&amp;rsquo;s Syndrome - an amazing family!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unexpected pricing</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/unexpectedpricing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 17:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/unexpectedpricing/</guid>
      <description>Derek Sivers highlights an interesting pricing approach in this article. He was asked to perform at a distant location. When the customer couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford the price they suggested reducing the performance time, hoping to reduce the price. Instead of doing the expected he raised his price. His reason was that they were paying for him to get to the location and then do the work where the work was the fun bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Workers</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/knowledgeworkers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 08:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/knowledgeworkers/</guid>
      <description>This is an excellent article that touches on some many areas including Amazon (again) and their structure. However the most interesting part for me is the section on the way to view knowledge workers in business:
“Knowledge-worker productivity requires that the knowledge worker is both seen and treated as an ‘asset’ rather than a ‘cost.’ It requires that knowledge workers want to work for the organization in preference to all other opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tailor Brands</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/tailorbrands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 09:16:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/tailorbrands/</guid>
      <description>I came across a link on Product Hunt to Tailor Brands who do automatic logo creation and branding. It is great to see them still doing well. I used them for my company logo, Sentio Ventures, shortly after they started in 2014!
Links
Tailor Brands
Sentio Ventures</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Could this revolutionize shopping?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/amazonshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 18:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/amazonshop/</guid>
      <description>Amazon just opened the first store with no cashiers or checkouts.
Using technology it has been able to do away with both of these traditional aspects of a shop and just let customers walk out, having worked out what they have purchased.
Will it revolutionize shopping? I am not sure in the short term as this is some quite impressive technology and I am not sure it scales to a normal shop or supermarket however it has the potential to really shake things up over time - or at least push the incumbent shops to think again.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>