<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>book on I learnt about ...</title>
    <link>https://ilearnt.com/categories/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in book on I learnt about ...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 07:00:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ilearnt.com/categories/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Armada by Ernest Cline</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/armada/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 07:00:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/armada/</guid>
      <description>Took me a little while to get into this book. It starts out in a school where a pupil spots a spaceship from his favourite video game. This then moves on to it being a precursor to an invasion by the aliens from the video game and the game itself was actually put together as training so the players could pilot drones in the war. A slightly surreal concept but pretty well executed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero to One by Peter Thiel</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/zerotoone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 07:00:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/zerotoone/</guid>
      <description>I had read a lot of good things about this book and it had sat on my Kindle for a long time. Really enjoyed the first half of the book but thought the second half was more focused on things that weren&amp;rsquo;t relevant to me. There were some statements made that were clearly opinions but were stated as facts. Overall a bit disappointing.
Links
Zero To One</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Strategy/Bad Strategy by Richard P. Rumelt</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/goodstrategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 08:53:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/goodstrategy/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had this book a while but never got around to reading it properly. One of my colleagues at work was listening to the audio version of it and recommended it. This was an excellent read and very relevant to what is happening at the company I am working at at the moment. For me the key takeaway was that what most people call strategy is not actually strategy but vision or goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blackout by Marc Elsberg</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/blackout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 21:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/blackout/</guid>
      <description>This story documents one scenario that could happen when the nightmare happens of a massive power cut across Europe. It starts with a number of threads and weaves them well together. It follows an Italian as he realizes it is a terrorist attack on the smart power meters. This destabilizes the power grid which takes down most of the grid across Europe. A second attack targets the power plants. This leads to a power cut across Europe that lasts days and the storyline of how they track down the cause and the perpetrators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaders Eat Last by Simon Sinek</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/leaderseatlast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 06:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/leaderseatlast/</guid>
      <description>I really liked Simon Sinek&amp;rsquo;s other books but didn&amp;rsquo;t get into this one as much - don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, it is still an excellent read and you can learn a lot.
The name comes from how officers in the US Marine Corp will eat last as opposed to most organisations where the leaders eat first. It covers why the best leaders think of others first and will put themselves at risk for others having created environments where they know others would do the same for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Your Life: How to Build a Well-Lived, Joyful Life by Bill Burnett and Dave Evans</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/designingyourlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 07:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/designingyourlife/</guid>
      <description>I was really looking forward to this book as I had listened to a podcast where they explained the ideas behind it. The two authors run a design course in Stanford that gets massively oversubscribed and has a huge impact on those who take it by looking at life as a design problem. The aim is to come up with lots of possible routes for your life that could be awesome and then design a path to achieve one of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kubernetes Book by Nigel Poulton</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/thekubernetesbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 07:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/thekubernetesbook/</guid>
      <description>At the moment I am having to get up to speed on a bunch of technologies relating to &amp;ldquo;DevOps&amp;rdquo;. This includes Kubernetes. I borrowed this book from a colleague and read it over the course of two days commuting. It provides a very good high level overview of all the main concepts of the platform.
As an introduction, which is exactly what I needed, it was perfectly pitched however if I was going to have to get my hands dirty with using the platform in anger then there are probably better options out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When The Game Was Ours by Jackie MacMullan, Larry Bird, and Magic Johnson</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/whenthegamewasours/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 07:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/whenthegamewasours/</guid>
      <description>On 12th June 1984 I was on a family holiday in the US. We had spent three weeks travelling around Florida and then up the east coast to finally end up in Boston. During the day we had a guided tour of the city and we were told that it was game seven of the NBA finals that night between the Boston Celtics and the Los Angeles Lakers.
I was only thirteen but, possibly as it was the last night of the holiday, managed to persuade my parents that I could stay up and watch the game.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>