<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>life on I learnt about ...</title>
    <link>https://ilearnt.com/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in life on I learnt about ...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 11:53:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ilearnt.com/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Family Breakfast</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/familybreakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 11:53:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/familybreakfast/</guid>
      <description>Someone I work with mentioned that each week he takes time to have coffee with his mum. This might sound quite normal but there are two parts that stand out for me.
Firstly it is the actual act of scheduling time to do this. It is very easy in today&amp;rsquo;s world to get so busy that we forget about the important stuff. Secondly, he lives in London and his mum lives in South Africa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep is your superpower</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/sleepisyoursuperpower/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 07:30:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/sleepisyoursuperpower/</guid>
      <description>This is one of the scariest videos I think I have ever seen. It is not a horror movie or a thriller - it is a talk about the impact sleep has on the body and in particular the impact a lack of sleep has. This includes increasing the risk of cancer, decreased brain function and reduced immune system. I am seriously reconsidering how I &amp;ldquo;do&amp;rdquo; sleep after watching this!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Summaries</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/booksummaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 07:34:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/booksummaries/</guid>
      <description>I read a lot of books - a bit less at the moment as I commute less - but still probably more than most people. However there are so many books I would like to read I can&amp;rsquo;t read them all. I still prefer to read the full book but sometimes book summaries are useful - either to get the key concepts or as a reminder of what I have previously read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bottlenecks</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/bottlenecks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 07:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/bottlenecks/</guid>
      <description>I really like Seth Godin&amp;rsquo;s blog - I could easily link to his posts every day - however occasionally a post really stands out for me. A recent post called Bottlenecks had an interesting observation that was a different way of thinking about them.
I worked for a company a long time ago where the person running the company insisted on everything going through them - whether it was important decisions like strategy or minor stuff like approving the purchase of paper clips!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antilibrary</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/antilibrary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 11:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/antilibrary/</guid>
      <description>I read a lot of books and once I start reading a book I normally finish it. This article proposes that it may be more valuable to have a bunch of books that are unread. Not sure I completely buy in to the proposition that &amp;ldquo;Read books are far less valuable than unread ones&amp;rdquo; however maybe I won&amp;rsquo;t feel so guilty buying a book and then leaving it unread.
Links</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Without Doing</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/learningwithoutdoing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 17:08:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/learningwithoutdoing/</guid>
      <description>I am back on the learning Scala trail and it is clear that just reading books and articles or watching videos won&amp;rsquo;t cut it. It needs to be hands-on coding.
This article highlights that some skills cannot be learnt without actual doing.
Links
Learning without doing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GeoGuessr</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/geoguessr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 07:17:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/geoguessr/</guid>
      <description>This is a very simple idea for a quiz. It drops you in a random place somewhere in the world and you use Google StreetView to work out where it is. If you are lucky you end up in a town or city, sometimes you end up in the middle of nowhere. It is amazing how much you can work out by looking at the flora or a random signpost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Change = Big Impact</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/disposablecups/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 17:35:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/disposablecups/</guid>
      <description>A simple change in message can lead to a big impact.
Without changing the price of the drink, the University of Winchester reduced the number of disposal cups used in a year by 34K. This was achieved by saying there was a &amp;ldquo;25p penalty&amp;rdquo; for using a disposable cup rather than a &amp;ldquo;25p discount&amp;rdquo; for using a reusable one.
Links
Plastic coffee cup waste is being cut by a simple change</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mother Of All Demos</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/motherofalldemos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 07:47:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/motherofalldemos/</guid>
      <description>There is a video of a demonstration given by Doug Engelbart in 1968 which is commonly referred to as &amp;ldquo;The Mother Of All Demos&amp;rdquo;. In the demo, he demonstrates a lot of technologies for the first time together that are common place today and some which we haven&amp;rsquo;t even achieved properly now:
 windows hypertext graphics efficient navigation and command input video conferencing the computer mouse word processing dynamic file linking revision control collaborative real-time editor (collaborative work)  One of the demonstrations that is particularly of interest to me is the chorded keyboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of the English Alphabet</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/englishalphabet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 08:29:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/englishalphabet/</guid>
      <description>A simple chart showing how the English alphabet evolved and how we ended up with what we have. It is particularly interesting how the Roman alphabet changed to become the English alphabet.
Links
Evolution of the English alphabet</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missing payment</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/missingpayment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 08:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/missingpayment/</guid>
      <description>I was due to be paid for some work earlier this month and the payment was from a foreign bank account into my account in GBP. The payment was made two weeks ago but never turned up in my account. After numerous phone calls with my bank and a lot of help from the CFO of the company I am working for (thanks Mario) we eventually managed to locate the payment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy is choice</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/privacyischoice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 08:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/privacyischoice/</guid>
      <description>A great quote from this podcast by 23andMe Co-Founder and CEO Anne Wojcicki &amp;hellip;
 &amp;ldquo;Privacy is not about not sharing, it is about choice&amp;rdquo;
 Links
Driving Discovery and Disruption</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pi</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/piday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 21:50:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/piday/</guid>
      <description>This page is devoted to maths and in particular pi. The answer to the second question on this page is unexpected and I love the energy the maths teacher brings to the class in the video. I had maths teachers but never one quite like this.
Links
Can you solve it? The Pi Day party starts here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Let Status Change The Conversation</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/statusconversations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 06:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/statusconversations/</guid>
      <description>I am probably like most people in that when I meet someone who I deem to be important the way I deal with them changes. It introduces a more reserved interaction with more careful responses.
It is something I am improving. I am now dealing with &amp;lsquo;C&amp;rsquo; level executives which in the past would have put me much more on the back foot.
Derek Sivers has written about a chat he had where he really clicked with someone and only later found out how important he could be to his life - which if he had known previously would have completely changed the way they interacted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning from terminally ill children</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/lifeandterminallyill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 07:23:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/lifeandterminallyill/</guid>
      <description>I am going to try and enjoy the small things in life and focus more on those close to me; something that is not always easy when caught up in the hustle and bustle of life.
Links
What terminally ill children taught this doctor about how to live</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stunning nature photographs</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/naturephotographs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 17:19:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/naturephotographs/</guid>
      <description>These nature photos are absolutely stunning. Some people have a gift for photography &amp;hellip; and I am not one of them.
Links
Winning photos from the International Garden Photographer of the Year 2018</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Water Refills</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/freewater/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 21:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/freewater/</guid>
      <description>This is such a simple idea and could potentially have a huge impact if it takes off - cafes and pubs filling up water bottles for free.
Links
Free Water Refill Stations: An Idea To End The Plastic Bottle Scourge</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancing without Sound</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/dancingwithoutsound/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 07:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/dancingwithoutsound/</guid>
      <description>My daughter loves dancing - always has done - whether it is street, contemporary or ballet. However she faces none of the challenges the dancers (and musicians) in this video face. I won&amp;rsquo;t spoil it here &amp;hellip; just watch.
Links
Dancing without sound</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unexpected pricing</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/unexpectedpricing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 17:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/unexpectedpricing/</guid>
      <description>Derek Sivers highlights an interesting pricing approach in this article. He was asked to perform at a distant location. When the customer couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford the price they suggested reducing the performance time, hoping to reduce the price. Instead of doing the expected he raised his price. His reason was that they were paying for him to get to the location and then do the work where the work was the fun bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Alternative Bucket List</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/alternativebucketlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 08:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/alternativebucketlist/</guid>
      <description>I have never formally made a bucket list. Sure, there are things I would love to do and some more than others but I have never written anything down.
This article has a different way of composing this list and the focus is definitely on people. It is basically the following:
&amp;ldquo;Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re in a hospital bed, connected to a tube. You have a pen and paper in hand. Would you really list anything about visiting a foreign country or an ocean escapade?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology: Am I past it?</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/pastit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 16:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/pastit/</guid>
      <description>This is an interesting post from Rob Conery, someone I&amp;rsquo;ve followed for quite some time, and his observations as he gets older about how he wonders if he is past keeping up with new technology.
I regularly get challenged with new roles and new technologies and often question myself but experience counts for a lot and life would be boring without challenges :)
Links
Modern Dev Team</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>