<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>work on I learnt about ...</title>
    <link>https://ilearnt.com/categories/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in work on I learnt about ...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2020, Mark Rainey - All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 15:10:22 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ilearnt.com/categories/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How we recharged the team with a fallow week</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/fallowweek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 15:10:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/fallowweek/</guid>
      <description>Due to the ongoing COVID situation the team had been struggling to stay focussed and motivated. The inability to go out, the lack of change of scenery and the sameness every day has been taking its toll. To try to address this we actively encouraged them to take time off - which, given the limitations on travel, was less appealing than it normally would be.
For those unable or unwilling to take time off we decided to introduce a &amp;ldquo;fallow week&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to change your day with meeting plans</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/meetingplans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 21:05:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/meetingplans/</guid>
      <description>I recently had a day where I had about 10 different meetings - all on different subjects. I knew that I would struggle to be productive in each of them if I turned up for them unprepared and had to switch subjects each time.
To solve this I created a simple document and added a heading for each meeting. Under each heading I made a simple bullet list of everything I wanted to cover or possibly discuss in the meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to easily implement successful remote team retrospectives</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/fullyremoteretrospectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 11:39:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/fullyremoteretrospectives/</guid>
      <description>As part of our processes we regularly hold retrospectives. We used to do this all in a room with post-it notes - a fairly traditional approach. We would set up 4 areas: Liked, Longed, Learned and Lacked and proceed to plaster post-it notes over the different sections. Once everyone had finished we would organise each section into themes and then discuss and agree actions.
Going fully remote has obviously meant we need to take a different approach and we now drive it from a shared document we create for each retrospective in Google Docs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boost productivity with meeting free days</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/meetingfreedays/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 16:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/meetingfreedays/</guid>
      <description>It is very easy for your work week to become a random collection of meetings - all with different attendees and different agendas. For developers in particular this can cause a huge hit on productivity as their day becomes disjointed and they are unable to stay focussed for the longer periods they need for their work.
We started seeing this with the team I am working with. Someone would see a big chunk of free time and schedule a meeting right in the middle of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A simple addition to every meeting</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/sharedmeetingdocument/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 12:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/sharedmeetingdocument/</guid>
      <description>We have a lot of remote meetings as most of our team work a significant amount of time from home. Face to face meetings are much better for some types of meetings - especially workshops and retrospectives. As the level of expected collaboration increases the more it favours face to face interactions.
We have also been far from optimal in capturing information from meetings and discussions. We have tended to capture the actions fairly well but have failed to adequately capture the &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; - i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speed up in the long term by slowing down in the short term</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/spreadingtheknowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 08:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/spreadingtheknowledge/</guid>
      <description>On most projects there is a tendency for someone involved to become the &amp;ldquo;expert&amp;rdquo; in one or more areas. As they become comfortable and more knowledgeable in an area they will naturally gravitate to picking up tasks related to it. The need to deliver as quickly as possible can also drive this as the person who knows most is likely to be the person who can do the work quickest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It always pays to leave well</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/leavingwell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 09:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/leavingwell/</guid>
      <description>When someone leaves a company there are two sides to it.
The first side is the way the employee behaves and handles themselves. I always aim to be professional and work hard until the moment I leave the office for the last time. I like to think that is one of the reasons my last four roles have involved word of mouth recommendations.
I have seen some people, who were excellent up to that point, almost switch off once they have announced they are leaving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to run a planning workshop</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/planningworkshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 08:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/planningworkshop/</guid>
      <description>We have just completed a two week exercise with the whole development team to identify, design and estimate the next phase of work. It started as an organic process as we found the best way to do this and then developed into a repeatable process for the latter functionality.
Before starting on the individual breakdowns we produced a list of things to consider for everything we were estimating. This mostly consisted of a list of functional requirements like logging, testing, documentation, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do we really need that meeting? - the forgotten costs</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/meetingcosts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 09:22:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/meetingcosts/</guid>
      <description>We had a meeting recently with 16 people on the video conference call. Due to poor planning and technical issues it took nearly half an hour to decide to postpone the meeting. That is eight man hours wasted - a whole day of work!
This article proposes an add-on to the calendar that informs the person booking the meeting how much the meeting will effectively cost the company. Love it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abolish performance reviews</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/abolishperformancereviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 06:41:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/abolishperformancereviews/</guid>
      <description>I have never been a fan of performance reviews. It may have been down to the way they were implemented at the places I worked however they never seemed to achieve what they were set out to do. The review would usually consist of going over the &amp;ldquo;achievements&amp;rdquo; for the past period and then setting a bunch of artificial goals for the next period. The only time these new goals were actually consulted was in the run up to the next review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working from home boosts productivity</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/workingfromhomeboost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 07:13:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/workingfromhomeboost/</guid>
      <description>I am fortunate with my current role that I am able to work 2-3 days per week from home. This saves me about 2.5 hours of commuting time per day as well as about £2000 per year.
A new study from Stanford University has shown that working from home can increase productivity significantly. There is a small proviso that working 100% of the time from home can also have a detrimental effect as it can lead to isolation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The bosses who change our lives</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/thebossesweremember/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 07:41:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/thebossesweremember/</guid>
      <description>I have been very fortunate in my career to have some exceptional bosses that have had a massive impact on my career.
Kim Ho
When I came out of university it was in the middle of a recession. Despite coming second in my whole year I had to send my CV out to 45 places before I got a single response. Fortunately I got the role and I have never been out of work since (in over 25 years).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the team size to deliver</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/reducingteamsize/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 18:15:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/reducingteamsize/</guid>
      <description>A project was struggling to deliver in time and the project manager resolved it by reducing the team size where the typical approach is to increase the team size. This decision was based on the overhead of communication and Brooks Law.
Links
Applying Brooks Law</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unorthodox leadership by letting others drive</title>
      <link>https://ilearnt.com/post/unorthodoxleadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 06:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ilearnt.com/post/unorthodoxleadership/</guid>
      <description>Steve Kerr, the coach of the Golden State Warriors basketball team, took an usual step recently by allowing his players to coach instead of him. He felt that things had become a little staid and wanted to shake things up &amp;hellip; it worked - they won by their highest margin of the season. Sometimes leadership is knowing when to step back.
Links
By Doing Something No One Expected, Golden State Warriors Coach Steve Kerr Taught a Brilliant Leadership Lesson</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>